■
-= NORM TEAM =-
-=本资源仅供学习测试,严禁用于商业途径=-
■
更多精彩 尽在 WWW.NORMTEAM.COM
压制：IamEureka　　特效字幕：IamEureka
大家把钱准备好，我们时间不多
BARTLEBY: Everyone, have your money ready. We only have so much time.
好了，说：“茄子” “茄子”
BARTLEBY: Okay, say, "Cheers!" Cheers.
说“鞋子” “鞋子”
Say, "Beer!" Beer!
说，“茄子”
Say, "Cheers!"
喵
(MEOWlNG)
格伦， 伙计，你得把那件衣服脱了
Glen, you got to take that shirt off, pal.
为什么？
Why?
汉兹， 你来解释一下好吗？
Hands, you wanna field this one?
伙计，这个驾照是伪造的
Uh, dude, you're getting a fake lD
而你身上穿的衣服表示你还是个高中生
and you're wearing a shirt that says you're in high school.
那又怎么样？
So?
好吧，随便，我待会儿帮你处理一下
Okay, whatever. I'll fix it later.
你继续
Just do what you were doing.
（喵） 你的猫叫真好听
(MEOWlNG) Give me some nice cat things.
- B！ - 哦，嗨，施瑞德.
SCHRADER: B! BARTLEBY: Oh, hey, Schrader.
这是怎么回事？
SCHRADER: What the hell is going on here?
放松点，伙计
Relax, pal.
我们会捐出5%给慈善事业的
Five percent goes to your favorite charity.
忘了告诉你，我借了你的钥匙用
Uh, I forgot to tell you, I borrowed your keys.
忘了告诉你，我借了你的钥匙用 起来
You borrowed my keys? Come on.
我需要他们
Well, I needed them. Ow.
我们在为美国青少年提供很重要的服务
We're providing a vital service to America's youth here.
- 下一个请上来，好吗？ - 不行，打住！
Could we get the next in line, please? No, we're not. Stay there!
这属于不良行为， B.
We're contributing to the delinquency of minors, B.
你知道如果我被逮住，将会怎么样？
Do you know what will happen to me if I get caught?
每天第八节课下课后
Every day after eighth period,
副校长马修斯就会来
Vice Principal Matthews comes in here.
他会带一本女性保健杂志
He picks up the women's fitness magazine
然后在这里打手枪！
and he snaps one off!
- 真的？ - 没错
BARTLEBY: Are you serious? Yes.
那麻烦了
That is a problem.
第八节还没下课，对吧？
Uh, okay, well, we still have the rest of eighth period, right?
我们赶快收拾东西，然后闪人
So, we'll just pack everybody up and get out of here.
好的，快点
Okay, let's go!
(BELL RlNGS)
该死！
Shit!
(ALL SlNGlNG DlSCORDANTLY) # America! America! ##
基恩斯! 基恩斯! 基恩斯!
Gaines! Gaines! Gaines!
好了，好的，停一下
Okay, good, good.
啊，太好了！ 马修斯副校长!
Ah, wonderful! Vice Principal Matthews!
真高兴你能来！
So glad you could join us!
这是怎么回事?
What the hell is this?
是合唱团排练，先生
It's Glee Club practice, sir.
我们在为毕业日做准备，这对我们很重要
We're just gettin' ready for Memorial Day. It's a big one for us.
学校没有合唱团
We don't have a Glee Club.
还没有成立，先生
Not yet, we don't, sir.
作为毕业班的学生，我们希望能够留下些什么
But as the graduating class, we wanted to leave behind
来激励我们的学弟学妹
a legacy that inspires future students
我们应该主动一点，而不应该浪费时间在…… 我也不知道
to take initiative rather than spend their time,
至少不会偷偷拿着妇女杂志，做些有伤风化的事
I don't know, privately defacing women's fitness magazines.
我是说，前两天我在找一篇
I mean, I went to read an article
关于无炭高级纺织面料的文章
about no carbs and higher reps the other day
- 发现两页纸…… - 你是个大混球
and the pages were... You are a rotten egg.
...好像是被某种天然的胶黏在一起 说够了没有
...as if by some natural adhesive. That'll be enough.
我真得减肥了
I need to cut the pounds
连这种黏糊糊的胶都…… 住口！
and I can't open the... Stop it!
弄不开…… 住口！
Whatever does it for... Stop it!
我说完了
That's all I'm gonna say.
感谢上帝，你要毕业了
Thank God you're graduating.
(BELL RINGING)
- 我是施瑞德家族中第四代 - 对不起
I'm the fourth-generation Schrader... Sorry.
读哈蒙学院的人，拜托 我知道
to go to Harmon College, okay? Yeah.
我绝对不能因为某些事情把它搞砸了！
I can't do anything to screw that up.
比如，因为伪造驾照而被逮住
You know, like, I don't know, getting busted for identity fraud.
瞧你，别闹了好吧？放松
Look at you. Would you stop, man? Relax.
我们都会去念大学的
We're all goin' to college, okay?
难以相信这句话居然出自一个
This is said by the guy who's been rejected... GlRL: Hey, B.
被七所学校拒收的人之口
...by seven schools.
嘿，我已经感受到压力了
Hey, I'm creating dramatic tension.
我对第八所大学很有信心
I got a good feeling about number eight! Ugh.
我被录取了！ 我被普林斯顿大学录取了！
I got in! I got in! I got into Princeton!
耶！耶！
Yeah! Yeah!
(WHOOPlNG)
我想他大概被普林斯顿录取了
Hey, I think that guy got into Princeton.
你怎么知道
Oh, what makes you say that?
我猜的
I don't know.
巴特比! 嘿！
Bartleby! Hey.
- 嘿，你好吗，莫妮卡? - 嘿，你好吗？
Hey, how are you, Monica? Hey, how are you?
很好，你认识施瑞德吗?
Good. Do you know Schrader?
不，我想不认识，哦！ 认识！我们……
No, I don't think so. Oh! Yes! We...
我们一起上过课……
I actually... We had a class.
哦，没错！
Oh, yeah.
那课我实在听不下去了， 所以坐的离你很远
My shit was all crazy. I sat way behind you.
- 哦，真抱歉 - 我也不认识你
Yeah. Sorry. SCHRADER: I don't remember you, either.
- 不好意思 - 没事
Sorry. It's all right.
我找你真的有事请
Um, anyway, I really wanted to ask you something.
听候调遣
Sure, anything.
我也觉得现在说有点太晚了
Um, you know, I know it's really late,
趁着还来得及……
but, um, last minute and everything,
- 你知道，毕业舞会就快到了 - 对
but prom is coming up soon, you know? It's okay. Yes.
在这之前，我家也会开一个派对
And I'm actually having a party at my house beforehand.
- 太棒了！ - 我是在想
Awesome! And I was wondering
你是不是愿意，呃…… 你是不是可以，呃……
if you'd like to, um... If you could, um...
- 我很愿意！ - 帮我们修剪一下草坪
I'd love to. ...mow our lawn.
- 修剪草坪？ - 是的
Mow your lawn? Yeah.
哦，真不好意思
Oh. I'm sorry.
我也很难为情，但是你知道
Yeah. I'm really embarrassed, but, you know,
割草机坏了 然后我妈妈就说：“去找巴特比！”
our mower's broken and my mom was just, like, "Ask Bartleby!"
很好啊！
That's cool!
- 告诉你妈妈我很乐意修剪草坪 - 真的?
I... Yeah. Tell your mother I would love to mow the lawn. Really?
当然
(CAR HORN HONKlNG) Of course.
- 太感谢你了！ - 没事
Thank you so much. Yeah, sure.
- 谢谢你 - 嘿，宝贝！莫妮卡！快来！
Thank you. Hey, babe! Hey, yo, Monica! Come on!
抱歉，我的走了
Sorry, I got to go.
- 再次表示感谢！ - 别客气
But thank you, again. Yeah, s-sure.
你确实帮了大忙了 哦，很高兴遇见你
You're really helping us out. Oh, great to see you.
还有你，见到你真高兴
And, hey, it was nice to meet, um, see you. Talk to you.
是的，我也是- - 很高兴遇见你
Yes, yes. It was-- It was so nice catching up with you.
- 好的，再见 - 再见，莫妮卡.
MONlCA: Yeah. Okay. Bye-bye. B-Bye, Monica.
真抱歉让你等我，宝贝
Hey, I'm sorry to keep you waiting, baby.
霍伊特·安布罗斯，霍伊特！
Hoyt Ambrose. Hoyt!
霍伊特·安布罗斯 这小子哪点比我强？
Hoyt Ambrose. What's that guy got that I don't have?
我只是缺少一辆车
I just need to get a car.
还有英俊的外表
And classic good looks.
#我们不是沉默不语的小孩
# We're not just kids to say the least
# 我们有昂贵的梦想
# We got ideas to us that's dear
# 马萨诸塞州立大学
# University of Massachusetts, please
“很抱歉的通知您……”
BARTLEBY: "l regret..."
# 都是教育 #
# It's educational #
难以置信，我竟然没有被州立大学录取！
BARTLEBY: I can't believe I didn't get into State!
难道我要求很过分吗？
I wasn't even aiming high with that one.
这是我的最后保障！
That was my fallback!
最垫底的学校！ 以防万一的！
It was my safety school, my fail-safe!
也许你只是，太普通了
Maybe you're just too average.
得了，得了
Hey, time out.
太普通？
Too average?
请注意，莉齐
Okay. Okay. Excuse me, Lizzie.
你在跟谁说话
R-R-Remember who you're talkin' to here.
我整整一年不用去上体育课
I didn't have to go to gym class for a whole year
因为我称自己对出汗过敏
'cause I claimed to be allergic to sweat.
还有一次 我成功的从医生那里开到证明说我有夜行症
Or what about the time I got the note from my doctor saying I was nocturnal
于是被允许可以边做梦边学习
and I was allowed to study in my dreams?
我让学校的一霸，弗兰克·达利 被学校开除了两年
I got the school bully, Frank Daley, kicked out for two years
因为我说他性侵犯我
because he was sexually harassing me
把我按在柜子上，然后我说我感到异常
by pushing me up against the locker and I said I felt something.
你瞧见了，这是天才的表现
I mean, come on. That was pure genius.
也许你不该写那篇叫做“我一无所知”的论文
Maybe if you didn't write an essay called "l Don't Have a Clue."
可那是事实！
Well, it's true. You know?
关于我的余生将怎样度过，我一无所知
I don't have a clue what I want to do with the rest of my life.
老爸老妈会杀了你的
Mom and Dad are gonna kill you.
相信我好了
O ye of little faith.
- 他们不会的 - 是吗？
They're not gonna kill me. Uh-huh.
我只要稍微耍点小花招
I just have to spin it
用一种他们可以理解的方式解释
and put it in terms they can understand.
我不能理解
I don't understand.
我也不能理解
I don't understand, either.
好吧，这么说吧
Okay, I figure it like this.
大学每年的学费是多少？ 20000美元？
The average cost of college is, what, $20,000 a year?
根据我从网上查到的统计
Now, according to these estimates that I got off the Web...
大家传阅一下
You can pass those around.
一个只有高中学历的人
Someone with no education beyond high school
在目前的就业情况下，一年可以挣20000美元
can expect to make about $20,000 a year in the current job market.
也就是说，接下来的四年
Now, that being said, over the next four years,
你们可以选择花费80000美元
you could either spend $80,000
或者，我可以挣80000美元
or I could make $80,000.
(CHUCKLES)
你难道不想上大学？
Are you saying you don't want to go to college?
不，我只是说，如果我去上大学
No. I'm saying that it is fiscally irresponsible
这从财政上来说不科学
for me to go to college. You know?
- 你是不是吸毒了？ - 哦，老天，没有
Are you huffing? Oh, God. No.
- 你发烧了？ - 你吸大麻？
Are you high? You're huffing grass?
不，我没有吸毒，也没有喝酒，我完全正常
No. I'm not huffing, Mom. I'm not stoned. I'm completely fine.
事实上，我现在再清醒不过了
In fact, I'm more clear and level-headed than I've ever been.
那好，收起你那套吧，巴特比.
Okay, cut the crap, Bartleby.
这个社会有它的准则
Society has rules.
第一条准则就是：上大学 恩
And the first rule is you go to college. Mmm-hmm.
你想拥有快乐而成功的人生吗？ 那就上大学
You want to have a happy and successful life? You go to college.
你想出人头地？ 那就上大学
If you want to be somebody, you go to college.
如果你想融入社会 就去上大学！
If you want to fit in, you go to college.
如果没有大学要我怎么办
Well, you know what? Maybe I didn't get into college.
你什么意思？
What do you mean?
所有的学校都拒收我
I didn't get accepted anywhere.
噢， 巴特比.
Oh, Bartleby.
该死
Damn it.
我就说了，他应该从初中开始准备上大学
I knew he should've started preparing for college in junior high
就像他妹妹
Iike his sister.
现在她做的很好 我做的很好
Now, she's got a shot. I've got a shot.
- 她做的很好 - 大家听着
She's got a shot. Listen, guys.
有很多成功人士没有上过大学
There are plenty of successful people who didn't go to college.
阿尔伯特.爱因斯坦，你们都知道
Albert Einstein, you know.
波卡洪塔斯从没有上过大学 （《风中奇缘》中的印地安公主）
Pocahontas never went to college.
克里·费尔德曼，还有 科里·海姆 （两人均为演员）
Corey Feldman and Corey Haim.
他们都事业有成
They had a great run.
还有刘易斯（《纳尼亚传奇》的作者） 和克拉克（鞋业大亨）
Both Lewis and Clark.
苏珊娜·萨默斯（电影演员） 波诺（U2乐队主唱）
Suzanne Somers. Bono.
我得去看看皮鞋匠那里是不是收学徒
I need to go check on the cobbler.
"皮鞋匠" 咕，咕，咕
"Check the cobbler." Glug, glug, glug.
我毫不关心波诺做了什么或者没做什么
You know, I really don't care what Sonny Bono did or didn't do.
你得上大学
You're goin' to college.
我告诉过你了
I told you so.
知道了
You were adopted.
(DON'T STOP PLAYlNG)
各位
MRS. SCHRADER: Everyone,
我想敬所有的毕业生一杯
I would like to propose a toast to our graduates.
2006年毕业的同学们
To the Class of 2006,
祝未来的大学四年
may the next four years of college
成为你们人生中最精彩的岁月
be the best years of your life.
老妈
MAN: Hear, hear. Mom.
(PEOPLE TOASTlNG)
嘿，伙计，怎么样
HANDS: Hey. Hey, man, what's up?
- 好啊， B? - 你好，伙计
What's up, B? How you doin'? What's up?
伙计，我发誓，如果再有一个人说
Dude, I swear, if one more person tells me
要上大学了，真兴奋这样的话 我就崩溃了
how excited they are to go to college, I'm gonna lose it.
伙计，我听说奖学金的事情了
Oh, man, I heard about the scholarship.
太变态了，你是我们州最棒的接球手
That's insane. You're one of the best receivers in the state.
曾经的吧，膝盖受伤就别想打棒球了
Uh, the best. And, uh, no knee, no football, man.
太过分了，接下来打算怎么办？
That sucks. What are you gonna do now?
我也不知道
I have no idea.
真是患难兄弟啊
That makes two of us, pal.
- 没什么大不了的，没什么大不了的 .
RORY: It's fine, it's fine, it's fine, it's fine, it's fine.
- 嗨，罗莉，怎么了？ - 嗨，什么？哦，没事，没什么大不了的
Hey, Rory. What's goin' on? Oh, hey. What? Fine. Nothing.
呃，我没有被耶鲁大学录取
Um, l--I didn't get into Yale.
我没有...没有被耶鲁录取
I did-- I didn't, I didn't get into Yale.
我没有... 没有被耶鲁录取
I didn't... I didn't get into Yale.
什么？难以置信
What? I can't believe that!
耶鲁大学没有容纳罗莉的地方
Well, there's no room for Rory at Yale.
成绩平平，家里有钱的孩子太多了
Too many rich kids with mediocre grades
而且，我猜今年有关系的家长也很多
and well-connected parents this year, I guess.
没有罗莉的容身之所 她从一年级就开始
No room for Rory, who's been working
为进耶鲁大学努力学习
since first grade to get into Yale.
罗莉， 她除了耶鲁没有申请第二所学校
Rory, who only applied to Yale and nowhere else.
我是故意的！
I had it all planned!
太完美了，B! 太完美了！
It was perfect, B! Perfect!
没什么大不了的！没什么！
And now it's nothing! Nada!
鸭蛋，零！
It's a goose egg!
好吧
Okay. Well.
上帝， 罗莉! 罗莉!
God, Rory! Rory!
她的处理方式很好
She's handling that really well.
去他妈的大学！
RORY: College is for pussies!
我得走了，老兄
All right. I got to get out of here, pal.
- 再等等看 - 好的，伙计，你也一样
Hang in there. All right, man. You, too.
- 巴特比! 嘿！ - 哦，你好，施瑞德先生，我正想……
Bartleby! Hey! Oh, hey, Mr. Schrader. I was actually just...
你吃蛋糕了吗？
Did you have any cake?
哦，你知道我不喜欢吃蛋糕
No, you know, I'm not much of a cake guy.
这蛋糕做的棒极了
Oh, it is a hell of a cake.
这蛋糕的口味从斯科特和塞斯 读哈蒙学院的时候就没变过
It is the same cake we got for Scotty and Seth when they got into Harmon.
哦，风水轮流转
Oh, ah, everything comes full circle.
- 杰伊，你好吗，老兄？ - 我真不知道……
Jay! How are ya, bud? Oh, I really don't...
- 嗨，施瑞德 - 嗨
Hey, Stu. Hey.
你的小儿子就快去一所好的大学了
I can't imagine your pride, knowing your youngest
一定很骄傲吧，如释重负？
is headed off to a good college. Must take a load off.
哦，别提了
Yeah, well, not to mention
负担卸下了，账单背上了
the load it takes off my bank account.
(ALL LAUGHlNG)
老爸
Dad.
没什么如释重负的
Nothin' like gettin' a load off!
你怎么样，巴特比?
What about you, Bartleby?
问的好，哈金先生
That's a good question, Mr. Harkin.
好在哪里，特雷贝克先生?
What's with the questions, Mr. Trebek?
你去哪里？
Where you goin'?
呃，我……
Um, l--l, well...
我没有，呃……
I didn't really, uh...
巴特比不好好努力，现在上不了大学了
Bartleby screwed around and now he's not goin' to college.
他糟蹋了自己的人生
He's thrown his life away.
这正是我想说的，谢谢老爸
Yeah, that's-- that's what I was gonna say. Thanks, Dad.
等等，南哈蒙理工学院？
SCHRADER: Wait. South Harmon lnstitute of Technology?
- 没错 - B， 你知道，缩写是狗屁（SHIT），对吗?
BARTLEBY: Yeah. B, you realize that makes it S.H.I.T., right?
狗屁？ 我随便想的，管他呢
S.H.I.T.? I was wingin' it. Whatever.
帮我建好网站就行了
Just finish building the website, please.
这也太疯狂了吧？
This is the act of a desperate, wildly unrealistic person.
B，你弄好了也发给我一份录取通知书
Yo, B, you have to hook me up with one of these acceptance letters, bro.
- 你是不是在搞笑，当然不行 - 为什么？
Are you kidding me? No way. Why not?
得了，要想奏效，就必须得保密
Oh, come on. The only way this is gonna work is if we keep it quiet.
即使这样，还是得从长计议
And even then, it's still a long shot.
伙计，我不管了，我总得做点什么
Dude, I don't care. I have to do somethin'.
我一丢了奖学金
The minute I lost my scholarship,
我老爸就开始考虑让我去开公交车了
my pop started talkin' about me getting my own bus route.
帮帮我
Help me. Please? Mmm.
你知道吗？
You know something?
为了大众的安全，我也不能让你去开公交车
For the safety of the public, I can't let you drive a bus.
太好了 但是记住
Sweet. But listen to me.
这只是权宜之计
This is just a temporary stopgap measure, okay?
- 明白吗？ - 明白
Nothing more. Gotcha.
太棒了，伙计们 你们俩
Bravo, guys. Great. Both of you guys.
我们可以先伪造一个学校 然后就可以开个毒品加工厂了
Let's start this fake college. And then we'll go start a meth lab somewhere.
- 这就是犯罪的开始 - 什么？
BARTLEBY: Come on. It's a gateway crime. What?
犯罪就是这样开始的
That's how these things start.
你知道吗， 施瑞德
You know something, Schrader,
你可以上一所好大学
you got into a great college.
前程似锦
And your future's lookin' really good,
我很为你感到骄傲，因为你是我最好的朋友
and I'm psyched for you, pal, 'cause you're my best friend and I love you.
我只是想让你帮我一个小忙
I'm talking about me coming to you, asking for your help.
做好这个网页
Just finish the damn website.
求你了
Please.
怎么样？
What do you say?
这就对了 好吧
There he is! Fine.
离我远点，你这个白痴
(HANDS CLAPPlNG) Get off me, you idiot.
但我们需要一些诸如教学目标什么的
But we need some sort of, like, mission statement or something.
你老爸肯定要看，我了解他，他很难缠
Your dad's gonna want to see that. I know him, he's a hard-ass.
嘿，孩子们，亲爱的！
Hey, kids. Honey!
嗨，你好吗
Hey. Hi. How are you? Hey.
这是什么？
JACK: What's this?
南哈蒙理工学院？ 这是什么？
South Harmon lnstitute of Technology? What's that?
嗯？看看
Mmm? What's that?
这是本地区最受尊敬的大学之一
One of the most respected schools in the area, that's what that is.
上面说什么？
Well, what's it say?
我得先打开看看
I gotta open it first.
快点哦
DlANE: Come on, hurry.
哦，我很紧张
Oh. I'm nervous.
"亲爱的巴特比，
"Dear Bartleby,
“祝贺你，你被录取了！”
"congratulations, you've been accepted!"
我被录取了!
I got in!
- 啊！感谢上帝 - 我被录取了
Aw, thank God. Thank God. (LAUGHlNG) I got in!
哦！老天
Hey-o! Oh! God!
- 亲爱的 - 我没事
Honey. I'm okay.
太棒了
Hey, this is great!
太令人激动了
It's so exciting!
南哈蒙理工学院是什么大学?
What the hell is South Harmon lnstitute of Technology? Yeah.
是哈蒙学院的姊妹学校之一
Oh, it's one of Harmon College's sister schools.
我从没听说过
I've never heard of it.
因为姊妹中最小的一个
Well, because it's the baby sister.
也是最严谨，保守的一所
It's the most discreet and unharmed of the sister schools.
你有关于这所学校的资料吗？
You got any literature on this place?
它有自己的网站，我给你看网址
Yeah, there's a website, I'll show you the link.
你成功了 你是个大学生了
You did it. You're a college boy.
哇
Wow.
你们想吃点么？
So you guys want to eat? GlRL: Yeah.
(GlRLS CHATTERlNG)
嗨，我恨我的生活
Hey! I hate my life.
我是个大除草机
I'm a huge tool.
玩得高兴
Have fun being hot.
巴特比!
Bartleby!
老爸，怎么了
Hey, Dad, what's up?
我看了网站
I took a look at that website.
哦
Oh.
酷
Cool.
看上去不像真的
It looks unreal.
假的？
Unreal?
是啊，难以置信
Yeah, it looks pretty unbelievable, huh?
看上去像是个很棒的大学
It seems like a solid place.
真的
Really?
给你
Here you go.
第一学期的学费一次付清
First semester's tuition. Paid in full.
太棒了
That's great.
哇，谢谢你老爸
Wow, thank you, Dad.
哦，对不起
Oh, sorry. Sorry.
谢谢，老爸
Thanks, Dad.
你妈和我等不及要把你送出去读书了
Your mother and l can't wait to drop you off.
我们需要做的是在哈蒙学院附近租一个地方
What we need to do is lease a place near Harmon
这样才能骗父母相信
so we can fool our parents. Yeah.
施瑞德，你知道哈蒙学院附近有什么地方可以租的么？
Hey, Schrad, do you know any places up near Harmon we can rent?
是的，我知道
Oh, yeah, I do, actually.
我总是随身携带废弃房屋清单
I carry around a list with me at all times
专门用于伪造大学用
of abandoned buildings for fake colleges.
伙计，我已经给你们开了一个银行户头
Dude, I started you guys a bank account already.
你还想怎么样？让我当你的房地产经纪人？
What do you want me to be, your realtor?
嗨，伙计们，好啊
Oh, hey, guys. What's up?
好啊， 格伦?
Hey, what's up, Glen?
嗨 嗨，格伦
GLEN: Hey. Hey, Glen,
你什么时候开始在便利店工作了？
when did you start working at the Kwik 'N Stop?
从我被所有的大学拒收时开始
Since I got boned, hard, by every college I applied to.
怎么了？
Why, what happened?
因为政治原因
Some political crap.
我SAT（Scholastic Assessment Test：美国高考） 考试得零分.
I got a zero on my SATs.
你只要在考卷上签个名
You know you get 600 points
就能得到600分，不是吗？
just for signing your name, right?
(SNlCKERS)
好了，谈正事
All right, let's get serious, man.
怎么去找一个看上去像大学的地方
Now, where we gonna find a place to pass off as a college?
嗨，伙计们，我知道一个地方
Hey, guys! I know a place.
你怎么知道这个地方的？
HANDS: How'd you know about this place?
我曾经在这里当过志愿者
RORY: I used to do volunteer work here.
这地方太棒了
SCHRADER: This place is awesome.
我终于可以得上肝炎了
'Cause now I can finally get hepatitis.
一鸟在手（谚语：比喻既得利益）
BARTLEBY: A bird in the hand, dude. A bird in the hand.
这是什么意思
SCHRADER: That doesn't make any sense.
这是一种说法
BARTLEBY: It's a saying. SCHRADER: What?
是未雕琢的钻石
A diamond in the rough.
但愿你们都有意外伤害保险
Hope you guys have hobo-stab insurance.
(METAL CLANKlNG)
太棒了，垃圾的诞生地
SCHRADER: Great. The birthplace of crack.
(TOOL CLATTERlNG)
太棒了
BARTLEBY: Hello, beautiful.
嘿，伙计们，别进去
Hey! Hey, guys, don't go in there.
这属于擅自闯入
This is breaking and entering.
施瑞德，别怕
Schrader, come on. Don't be scared.
谁怕了？ 我才不怕，是你怕了
Who's scared? I'm not scared. You're scared.
施瑞德 你不想尝尝Dr.Pepper（软饮料）的新口味？
Schrader, you were scared to try the new flavor of Dr Pepper.
这是我们俩的秘密，汉兹
I told you that in confidence, Hands.
施瑞德， 你换牙的时候也害怕
Schrader, you were afraid when your tooth fell out,
因为你害怕那个同性恋牙医
because you were terrified of the tooth fairy.
这种害怕很正常
That's actually a legitimate fear.
她一直盯着我
She was rifling through my shit.
随便你，那你就呆这里吧
Okay, Fine, whatever, dude, stay here.
好的，我会的
Fine. I will.
好了，说真的
Okay, guys, seriously,
我可不想一个人呆着 墙上开始淌血了
I don't want to be here alone when the walls start to bleed.
我们不用整个翻新
BARTLEBY: We don't have to renovate the whole place.
只要对某些关键部位修正一下
We just have to focus on essential areas.
要整理大厅，走廊
We got the--the main lobby. Hallway.
宿舍 宿舍，没错
Dorm rooms. Dorm rooms, exactly.
我觉得这方法可行 太棒了
I think this could really work. Huh? It's awesome!
帮我拿一下 好
Can you hold that? Yeah.
只要我们想做，再做些体力活
Guys, a little can-do attitude, some elbow grease,
比如施瑞德的一个微笑
maybe a smile from Schrader.
就像整理自己的房间一样
It's like cleaning up your room, you know?
欢迎来到南哈蒙理工学院
Welcome to the South Harmon lnstitute of Technology.
太棒了 一个好的开端
HANDS: Atta baby. The beginning of good things.
是的
RORY: Yeah.
(BARTLEBY EXCLAlMS)
(SCREAMlNG SHRlLLY)
施瑞德，怎么回事？
Schrader, what the hell was that?
呃，真丢脸
Um, this is embarrassing.
你不是在开玩笑吧
Are you kidding?
如果你们不告诉别人
It would be really cool
我尖叫的声音原来是这样的 我会非常感激
if you guys wouldn't tell people I scream like that.
# 我们百无聊赖
# Had an atomic bore
# 在2004年
# In 2004
#我们拼命搞怪
# Did some atomic tricks
# 在2006年
# In 2006
准备，推
Ready, set, go.
哇!好了
Whoo! All right.
嗨，格伦.
Uh, whoa, Glen.
嘿，B.
Oh, hey, B.
你在这里干嘛呢，伙计？
What are you doing here, buddy?
罗莉告诉我的
Rory told me about it.
你在干什么？我们得保守秘密
What are you doing? We were gonna keep this place a big secret.
可是他没有别的地方可去
But he didn't have any place to go.
他被便利店开除了
He got fired from the Kwik 'N Stop.
真的？他们为什么开除你？
Is that true? Why'd you-- Why'd you get fired?
因为我把虾做成了虾泥
I got fired for making a shrimp slushee.
哦，真恶心
That's disgusting. See?
你为什么这么做
BARTLEBY: Why would you do that, pal?
因为我饿了，还有点渴
'Cause I was hungry and thirsty.
哦，老天
Oh, God.
# 我们百无聊赖
# Had an atomic bore
# 在2004年
# In 2004
# 我们拼命搞怪
# Did some atomic tricks
# 在2006年
# In 2000
# 五， 七
# Five, seven
(YELPS)
# 九
# Nine
# 我们百无聊赖
# Had an atomic bore
# 在2004年
# In 2004
# 我们拼命搞怪
# Did some atomic tricks
厨房烂透了
This kitchen is bitchin'!
这里是卫生间……
And this'll be the bath...
(ALL EXCLAlM)
关门
SCHRADER: Close the door. HANDS: Shit!
(FLlES BUZZlNG) Close it!
#我们百无聊赖
# Had an atomic bore
#在2004年
# In 2004
#我们拼命搞怪
# Did some atomic tricks
#在2006年
# In 2006
#我们出发太晚
# Got out way late
# 在2008年
# In 2008
# 我要再试一次
# I'm gonna do it again
#哦，耶，耶#
# Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah #
从这里出发到功成名就还很遥远
STU: It takes 10,000 steps to get from here to greatness.
千里之行
And this right here,
始于足下
this is step one.
祝你好运，儿子
Good luck, Son.
安布罗斯先生 你知道为什么哈蒙是一所著名的大学？
VAN HORNE: Mister Ambrose, do you know what makes Harmon a great college?
拒收
Rejection.
一所学校的好坏
The exclusivity of any university
取决于它所拒收的
is judged primarily by the amount of students
学生数目
it rejects.
不幸的是，最近几年
Unfortunately, for the last few years,
我们所拒收的学生数目
we have been unable to match the amount of students
远比不上耶鲁，普林斯顿，甚至斯坦福
that Yale, Princeton, or even Stanford rejects,
主要原因是硬件上的局限性
primarily because of our physical limitations.
但这一切都将改变了
But all that is about to change.
耶鲁有一个 普林斯顿也有一个
Yale has one, Princeton has one.
现在哈蒙学院也将拥有一个
And now Harmon College will have
久负盛名的入口大道
the prestigious entranceway it deserves.
青翠的草坪区
A verdant buffer zone
容纳知识，排除无知
to keep knowledge in, and ignorance out.
- 这是个很好的主意，先生 - 没错
That is a great idea, sir. Yes, it is.
现在，安布罗斯先生
Now, you, Mr. Ambrose, are chairman
作为学生会外联部的主席
of the Student Community Outreach Committee.
我要你去联系这些临近社区的
I need you to secure all these decrepit properties
陈旧建筑的主人
in the neighboring community.
以便能够拆除它们来腾出空间
So that we can demolish them to make room
建造范霍恩大道
for the Van Horne Gateway.
大家瞧
You know what?
看上去真的不错
This actually looks like the real deal.
我不想过份乐观
Guys, I don't want to be too overly optimistic,
但我想这应该能行
(CELL PHONE RlNGlNG) but I think this could work.
看上去非常专业，喂？
It really looks professional. Hello.
嘿，孩子，你在哪？
Hey, kid, where the hell are you?
哦，我在…… 听着
Oh, I'm, uh... Listen.
我又去看了学校主页
I took another look at that website.
怎么上面竟是废话套话？
What's all this "be what you want to be" crap?
不不，老爸，他们只是必须写这些东西
No, no, Dad, they just-- they just have to say stuff like that
以免遭到起诉
just to keep from being sued.
听上去的确是狗屁不通
Yeah, well, sounds like a bunch of crap to me.
我想见见你们的院长
Glen, go long. Set up a meeting with the dean.
(GLEN EXCLAlMlNG)
- 院长? - 老天!
The dean? Jesus. Mother of hell!
大学总该有个院长的，对吧？
Your college does have a dean, doesn't it?
- 我没事! - 当然，当然有院长
I'm good! Yes, of course the college has a dean.
可是老爸，你知道他很忙的
Dad, you know, he's a busy guy, though, you know,
他可不能随随便便的就跟家长见面
he can't just, uh, set up a meeting with parents.
听着，我付学费了，就有权利见院长
Listen. If I'm paying for it, I'm meeting with the dean.
我必须确认你接受的教育和我一样， 真正的教育
I want to make sure you have the same education I did. A real education.
- 早餐8：00 - 等等，老爸，我不能，我不能，该死！
Dinner's at 8:00. Wait, Dad, Dad, Dad, I can't-- I can't... Aw, shit.
我得把这个角上修正一下
I gotta trim this corner right here. I think I got poisoned.
- 怎么了，B? - 我有个小麻烦
What's up, B? We got a little problem.
- 什么？ - 刚刚谁打的电话，巴特比?
What? Who was that, Bartleby?
我们得去找个院长
We gotta find a dean.
生活中要分清楚想要的和需要的
In life, it's important to distinguish between need and want.
你认为你想要某样东西， 那是因为你以为可以得到
You think you want something because you've been conditioned to want it.
我要Pump（锐步球鞋）！
I want the Pump!
我们没有Pump！
I don't got the Pump.
看看 我们有蒂姆·邓肯（NBA球星）的阿迪达斯系列
Look, oh, I got the Tim Duncan Adidas Cool-D's.
我要Pump!
I want the Pump!
听着，你这个傲慢无礼的小屁孩！
Listen, you insolent little snot,
此刻在亚洲，很多小孩正在为你缝制该死的鞋
there are kids right now in Asia who are sewing your stupid shoes together,
好让家人今晚能吃上晚饭
so that their family can have a bowl of rice to eat tonight!
这是个馊主意
This is the worst idea of all time.
你叔叔本曾经是个天才
Your Uncle Ben used to be a genius.
- 他一定成 - 妈妈！
He'll be fine. BOY: Mom!
你做什么了？
WOMAN: What did you do?
都是你惯坏了这个孩子
You're the one who emotionally crippled the kid.
你知道吗？也许他有弱智
You know what? Maybe he's retarded.
真高兴我妈已经死了
I'm glad my mother's dead.
他只是过的不太顺心
He's just having a bad day.
哦，老天
Oh, my gosh.
你想让我当你学校的院长？
You want me to be the dean of your college?
不，我只是想让你假装院长
No, I want you to pretend to be the dean.
只要一天
It's just for one day.
也许谢尔曼忘了告诉你
Uh, perhaps young Sherman didn't share this with you.
我已经退休了，我不再教学生了
I've retired, I'm no longer a shaper of young minds.
真的？
Oh, really?
是的，确切地说，他是被开除了
Yeah, well, technically, he was fired.
那不是事实，我受够了教育界的这一套
That's not true. I got fed up with the education racket.
所以我退出了
So I quit.
我发辞呈了
I did send in my resignation
以一种非正常的方式
in a rather unorthodox fashion.
没错，你给院长寄了一包狗屎
You sent the dean of the university a bag of dog shit.
- 这是一种比喻 - 表示什么？
It was a metaphor. For what?
表示：“你就是一陀狗屎！” 哦
For "You're full of shit!" Oh.
- 这不是比喻 - 这就是比喻
That's not a metaphor. That's a metaphor.
或者暗喻，隐喻
Oh, semantics, schmantics.
三年以前我就厌倦了这一套东西
Three years from now, I'm finished with this crap.
我要去巴布亚新几内亚 我不干了
I'm goin' to Papua New Guinea. I'm outta here.
你要去哪里？
Wh-Where-- Where you going?
反正不干了
I'm going off the grid.
去他妈的公民权 去他妈的镇痛期
No more, uh, franchises, no more Botox,
去他妈的“嘿，我们再克隆一只羊”
no more "Eh, oh, let's clone another goat."
也去他妈的什么反性侵犯条例
And certainly no more sexual harassment suits.
说：“嗨，你的乳头很漂亮”有什么问题？
What's wrong with saying, "Hey! Nice tits."
什么时候说才算正常？
When did that go out the window?
好了，本，我只是想请你
Okay, Ben, all I'm asking you
随便和家长握握手什么的
is just shake a couple hands with some parents,
然后说：“你好，我是院长”之类的
say, "Hi, I'm the dean," whatever.
如果我们付钱给你怎么样？
What if we pay you?
别用你的金钱来玷污我的名誉
Don't sully my dignity with your cash.
你在这儿！你又让一个孩子哭了？
There you are! Did you make another child cry?
不是我的错，这孩子天生爱哭。你这个小杂种！
It's not my fault the kid's a crybaby! Little dipshit.
- 你是个混蛋！ - 你才是个混蛋！
You're an asshole! You're an asshole.
你的确是个混蛋，你被开除了！
You are an asshole. And you're fired.
也许我们可以继续谈谈刚才的事
Perhaps it is time to move on.
不过我得带上我的房子
But I get to bring my house.
成交
Deal.
- 右还是左？ - 右！
Right or left? Right.
- 哪个右边？ - 你说了算
Whose right? Your call.
- 你这个白痴 - 你弄反了
You're an idiot! You're upset.
跟着你的感觉走吧
Go with what you feel.
大概还有12英尺
You got about 12 feet.
(CRASHlNG)
完美
Perfect.
混球
Asshole.
好了，大家笑一下
RORY: Okay, smiles, everyone.
大学第一天
First day at college.
颜色怎么这样？ 屎黄色？
What's up with these colors? Shit brown? Really?
- 格伦选的 - 我就知道
Glen picked 'em. Of course he did.
你哪里找来的这些人？
Where'd you find all these people?
呃，我志愿参加了一个“大家学英语”的活动
Uh, I volunteer at an English-as-a-second-language program.
这些是我的学生，我告诉他们 如果想及格
These are my students. I told them if they wanted to pass,
他们必须成功的融入
they'd have to successfully assimilate
美国大学校园的氛围
into the American college environment.
哦！家长来了！
Whoa! The parents are here!
好了，伙计们，该我们了！
Okay! We're on, guys!
看我们的表演！
Okay, people, it's showtime!
哇
DlANE: Wow.
- 看我没骗你吧 - 哦，完全没有
BARTLEBY: No frills around here. DlANE: Oh, none at all.
看那个常春藤，雕像还有红墙， 实打实的学校
None of that, uh, that ivy, or gargoyles, or mahogany, it's the real deal.
实打实吧？
The real deal, huh?
没错，孩子，完全没错
This is it, kid. This is it.
这是你人生的重要时刻，把行李拿进去吧
The big moment. Take this in. Ah.
真令人激动，我兴奋死了
It's exciting, it's scary.
很令人激动 快看，太棒了
It's really scary. Oh, look! Oh, it looks great.
是的
Okay.
这里在干什么？
LlZZlE: What's going on here?
我们好像少了一个参观者
Okay, we lost one of the campers.
一个好奇的参观者
Curious campers.
你在干什么？ 不许这么做！
What are you doing? Don't do that. Don't do that.
亲爱的
(GROWLlNG PLAYFULLY) Honey.
没事，好了我们到了
Take it easy. Okay, here we are. Let's...
(ELECTRlCAL BUZZlNG)
那是怎么回事？
What the devil is that? Oh.
学校的供电系统的电泳
That's just a surge of collegiate energy.
大学都这样
It's college for you.
左边是我的宿舍，老爸
Take a left up here for the dorm room, Dad.
哦，你们大家能等一下吗
Oh, uh, can you hang on a second?
我现在必须要用一下洗手间
I just really gotta go to the bathroom a minute, you know.
哦，天哪，我只是……
Oh, Jesus Christ. I just wanna...
不不不！
No, no, no, no, no!
呃，这是，这是男厕所
Uh, it's, that's, it's the men's room.
你不能进去
You can't go in there.
你就不能在外面等我……
Well, can't you just stand outside...
黛安，你就不能等我们到餐厅吗？
Diane, can't you wait till we get to the restaurant?
嗨，回头见，拉希德 数学课上见
BARTLEBY: Hey, I'll see you, Rasheed. I'll see you in math class.
你还欠我30块钱，别忘了
You owe me 30 bucks, by the way.
他真爱开玩笑
You jokester.
- 我们到了，你们还记得汉兹吗？ - 嗨，基恩斯太太
Here we are. You remember Hands. Hey, Mrs. Gaines.
嗨，这是我家人
Hey, hi. The fam.
- 你看上去气色不错 - 谢谢
You look great. Well, thank you.
我第一次看到的时候，我都不相信自己要住在这里
When I first saw it, I was like, I gotta live here?
难以置信，但这却是就是宿舍
I can't believe this. But it's a dorm room.
- 基恩斯先生 - 达利尔，过的怎么样？
Mr. Gaines. Daryl, how are you, partner?
- 哇，好大的握力
Oh, thunder grip.
为什么窗户外有铁栏杆？
Why are there bars on the window?
噢，为了防止有人不小心掉出窗外
Oh, that's so nobody accidentally gets thrown out.
很好，这里的学习环境很好
It's fine. It's a good learning environment.
没有太多不必要的东西，可以安心学习
Not a lot of extras. You'll study harder.
没错，你看都是蓝色的，还有墙
Yes. We will, because of the blue and the sparse walls.
我同意你的观点
I agree with you, sir.
这些是什么？
What are these?
这是为了以防万一有地震
That's in case of an earthquake.
嗯，没关系，嗨，我们去见院长
Uh, never mind that. Hey, let's go meet the dean.
- 呃？ - 院长？
Huh? The dean.
过来，亲爱的
Come here, honey. Come on.
(CHATTERlNG)
- 怎么走？ - 妈妈，往右边走
DlANE: Which way? Take a right there, Mom.
肯定很有趣
It's gonna be fun.
你知道很多人都说
You know, a lot of people say
读大学的时期是青年男女们
that college is the time when young men and women
拓展视野，形成世界观的时期
expand the way that they look at their world,
是他们尝试新事物和新思想的时期
when they open their minds to new ideas and experiences
并且是他们漫长旅程的开始
and when they begin that long journey
从一个无知的少年
from the innocence of youth
成长为肩负责任的成年人
to the responsibilities of adulthood.
听上去是不是狗屁不通？
Now isn't that a load of horseshit?
(GUFFAWlNG)
(TlTTERlNG)
什，什么？
W-What?
你能不能把刚才的话向我们解释一下？
Could you explain that to us a little more?
呃，刘易斯先生，你为什么不跟他们讲讲
Uh, Dean Lewis, why don't you tell them
南哈蒙的办学理念？
a little bit about the philosophy here at South Harmon?
好吧，我们向这些孩子抛出一大堆诱人的字眼
Look, we throw a lot of fancy words in front of these kids,
吸引他们来上学
in order to attract them to going to school,
并自以为他们可以因此而获得美好前程
in the belief that they're gonna have a better life.
我们都知道自己所做的
And we all know that all we're doing
是培养下一代的
is breeding a whole new generation
卖主和买主！
of buyers and sellers.
Buyers and sellers!
皮条客和妓女！ 皮条客和妓女！
Pimps and whores. Pimps and whores!
向他们灌输的东西将会让他们一生自责 并且变得优柔寡断
And indoctrinating them into a life-long hell of debt and indecision.
- 我…… - 呃……
I... Um...
我不明白
I--I just don't understand.
难道还要我一勺一勺的喂你？
Do I have to spoon-feed it to you?
孩子们想上学
Look, there's only one reason
只有一个原因
that kids want to go to school.
该死的
Holy shit.
是什么呢？
Which is?
找一份好工作
To get a good job.
一份薪水不错的好工作
To get a good job, with a great starting salary.
我完全同意
I couldn't agree more.
(SlGHlNG)
听你这么评论教育
It is so refreshing to have somebody
真是醍醐灌顶
approach education so rationally.
真他妈的棒！
Fuckin' A!
老爸，啊！
(KNUCKLES CRACKlNG) Well, Dad. Ow.
(MOANS)
妈
Oh, Mom.
你让我们感到骄傲，孩子
You make us proud, kiddo.
我会努力的
I'll try, Dad.
不用为我担心，好吗？
Don't worry about anything, okay?
- 再见，亲爱的 - 安全带！
Bye, honey. Seat belts.
展翅高飞吧
Spread your wings.
我会飞的，你得让我去飞
I'm gonna fly. You gotta let me fly.
- 再见，莉齐 - 再见！
Bye, Lizzie. Bye!
再见
Bye!
(SlGHS)
我们现在干什么？
So what do we do now?
我的朋友，我们现在念大学了
Well, my friend, we're in college now.
我们想干嘛就干嘛
We can do whatever we want.
真有你的，B
Gotta hand it to you, B.
其他伙计们在教室里受煎熬
Kids everywhere are busting their ass in the classroom,
而我们却在这里杀外星人
and we're killing aliens, dude.
- 这比学习好多了 - 我们就是在学习，伙计
This is way better than learning. We are learning here, pal.
我们在学习当外交失败以后 通向文明的代价将会多么惨重
We're learning the dire cost to civilization when diplomacy fails.
我们正在学习政治学
We're learning political science right now.
(LOUD KNOCKlNG AT DOOR)
怎么…… 怎么回事？
What the... What the hell is that?
(KNOCKS FASTER)
是谁？
Who is it?
阿波纳斯·达尔文·杜兰普，先生
ABERNATHY: Abernathy Darwin Dunlap, sir.
你好！
Hi, there!
你叫什么名字？?
What's your name?
我叫阿波纳斯·达尔文·杜兰普
My name's Abernathy Darwin Dunlap.
但你可以叫我A.D.D.
But you could call me A.D.D.,
其实我的确有A.D.D.
on account of the fact that I have A.D.D.,
也就是“注意力涣散失调症”
which is Attention Deficit Disorder and you know,
我六岁的时候，大家以为这只是因为我太爱吃糖了
everyone used to think it was just an addiction to sugar when I was six,
我老妈经常哭，因为她认为我不可能
and my mom used to cry because she thought I would never be,
成为一个有健全社会能力的人
Iike, a fully functioning member of society,
就像我的邻居，他有退役军人综合症
Iike my neighbor who has Legionnaire's Disease.
哦……
Oh...
这里已经不再是精神病院了
This is no longer a mental health facility.
抱歉帮不上忙
I'm so sorry we can't help you.
- 祝你好运，伙计 - 我不需要医院！
Good luck to you, pal. (YELLlNG) I don't need a hospital!
好，好吧，那你在这里干嘛？
Okay, okay, wh-wh-what are you doing here, then?
除非我看错网站了
Well, unless I misread the website,
我是来报道的！
I'm here for orientation!
哦，你差点吓着我了，还不止一点点
Oh, you scared me for a second. In more ways than one.
你是在找哈蒙学院
Uh, you're looking for Harmon College,
就在那个坡下面
it's just right on up the hill.
祝你好运，过得愉快
But good luck, have fun. Go, Harmon.
不，我是在找南哈蒙理工学院
No! I'm looking for South Harmon lnstitute of Technology
因为只有这所学校收我
because, well, it's the only place I got accepted
我是来念我的英语语言学位的
and I'm looking to pursue my degree in English
或者法律，或者动物管理 随便什么！
or law or animal husbandry or anything really!
你刚刚说你被这里录取了？
Did you just say you got accepted here?
是的，没错，我们都被录取了
Well, yeah, yeah, yeah, we all did.
什么？
What?
#看看这些孤单的人们
# Look at all the lonely people
非常感谢你
Thank you so much!
# 看看这些孤单的人们
# Look at all the lonely people #
天哪，好大的派对
Oh, God. Holy balls.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
BOY: Move, fool.
哦，看，那是我以前的女朋友萨拉·帕尔芬
Oh, look, there's my old girlfriend, Sara Pelfan.
你伤透了我的心！
You broke my heart!
求你了
(WHlMPERlNG) Please.
哦，对不起，家长只能送到这里
Oh, uh, sorry, sorry. No parents allowed past this point.
这是咱们学校的规矩
It's part of our philosophy here at South Harmon.
我们要让你们的孩子独立
We need to mold your kids into individuals,
第一步就是
and the first step is to
切断家长- 孩子这层关系
(WHlSTLES) sever the ties of the parent-child relationship.
带他走吧
Take him.
我们很高兴拉里能被某个地方收留
We're just glad Larry got in someplace.
现在我们的麻烦没了
He's your problem now.
再见，宝贝，别咬人！
Bye, hon. No biting!
嗨，拉里
Hey, Larry.
很高兴见到你，进去吧
Okay, good talk. Go on in there.
你会习惯的，拉里，但愿别
You're gonna fit right in, Larry. Unfortunately.
我们怎么办？
What are we gonna do?
这本来应该是个秘密
This is supposed to be a secret.
是啊，我看已经被揭穿了
Yeah, well, I guess the secret's out.
你去查查看邮箱到底怎么回事 我去找施瑞德，好吗？
You go check the P.O. box, I'm gonna go find Schrader, okay?
嘿，会员朋友，欢迎来到B.K.E.之家
Hey, pledge guy, welcome to B.K.E. House.
我能为你拿一下西装吗？
Can I take your blazer for you?
进去吧，你的未来就在前方
Get in there, your future is right in there.
- 谢谢你 - 不用客气
Thank you. All right.
哦，该死
BARTLEBY: Oh, shit.
哦，老天 我真的很抱歉
GlRL: Oh, my gosh. I'm so sorry. Sorry.
巴特比，你好吗？ 嗨，你好
Bartleby. Hey, how are you? Hey, how you doing?
真对不起，把你的外套弄脏了
Good. I'm so sorry about your jacket.
别担心，这...这不是我的衣服
Dude, don't worry about it. It's-- It's not even my jacket.
太好了，那么，你怎么会在这里？
Perfect. So, what are you doing here?
我在找施瑞德，你有没有看见他？
I'm, I'm looking for Schrader, actually. Have you seen him?
呃，没有
Uh, no, I haven't.
嗨，我是谢尔曼·施瑞德.
Hey, I'm Sherman Schrader.
待会儿见
I'll catch up with you.
嗨
Hey.
我是谢尔曼·施瑞德 好吧
I'm Sherman Schrader. Okay.
太有意思了，我在一旁看你们
This is fun. I'm just gonna hang back
打桌球吧
while you guys shoot around and stuff, you know.
哦，该死
Oh, shit.
我来处理
I got it.
(EXCLAlMS)
哦，这是，呃，这是G号杆
Oh. That's a.. It's a G chord.
我曾经才卡百利桌球队呆过
I used to play in a Cranberries tribute band.
呃，后来解散了
Uh, we disbanded.
嗨！你是谢尔曼·施瑞德 是的
Hey, you're Sherman Schrader. Yeah.
- 霍伊特·安布罗斯 - 没错，我知道
Hoyt Ambrose. Yes, right. I know.
对，你是男生联谊会的主席
Yes. You are the president of this whole fraternity.
- 没错 - 你和莫妮卡·摩兰德交往
That's right. Right. You date Monica Moreland.
- 的确如此 - 对
That I do. Right.
- 我打手枪的时候会想她
I think about her when I masturbate.
(COUGHS)
- 什么？ - 什么？
What? What?
(MUMBLlNG)
我不是故意说的
I didn't mean to say that.
呃，谢尔曼的父亲和我父亲以前就是联谊会的会友
Yeah. So, uh, Sherman's father pledged alongside my father back in the day.
哦，你是世袭家里的传统
Oh, so you're the legacy.
没错，传统！
That's right. Legacy!
你可能……你打球的时候可能需要这个
You need... You probably need this to play, actually.
原来在这里吗？
Was it here?
呃，还是在这里？那里？
Uh, was it there? Was it...
那你现在在这里念书吗？还是……
So--So do you go to school here now, or...
哦，不是 我在南哈蒙念书
I don't. Uh, I go to South Harmon.
你说南哈蒙?
Did you say South Harmon?
是的
Yes, I did.
- 哦，那是什么学校？ - 呃……
Oh, what's that? Hmm?
南哈蒙是什么学校？
Wha-What's South Harmon?
南哈蒙是……是一所大学
South Harmon is... It's a college,
规模比较小的大学，非常，非常小
just a very small college. Teeny, tiny college.
- 那太棒了，祝贺你 - 谢谢
That's great. Well, congratulations to you. Thank you.
- 嗨，宝贝 - 嗨
Hey, sweetie. Hey!
哦，天哪，我真高兴……
Oh, my gosh, I was so excited for you...
给我一分钟时间，好吗？谢谢
Actually, can you just give me just one sec, okay? Thanks.
嗨，老兄，我是霍伊特·安布罗斯
Hey, winner, Hoyt Ambrose.
弗洛伊德·潘布罗斯
(LAUGHS) Floyd Pambrose.
太奇怪了，我们的名字很押韵
That's weird. Our names rhyme.
是啊，这奇怪
Yeah, that is pretty weird.
真有趣，欢迎到B.K.E.
That's kind of crazy. Welcome to B.K.E.
多谢.这不错，我喜欢这
Thanks. It's great. I love it here.
- 压抑的异性关系 - 噢
All the sexually repressed energy. Oh.
我喜欢这，很多秘密的反犹太主义 你也知道
I love it. A lot of anti-Semitism, but under the rug, you know.
我喜欢你的处事方式
I like it, I like the way you handle your business.
谢谢，非常感谢
Thanks. Thanks a lot.
好了，为什么不到处走走认识下新朋友
Well, hey, why don't you just hang around and meet some guys?
不了，谢谢 我们不一样
Oh, no, thanks, man, I'm not into guys.
我完全尊重你的生活选择 好运
I totally respect your lifestyle choice, though. And good luck with it.
你父母也许不同意 但我会
Your parents probably don't get it, but I do.
- 下次见，莫妮卡 - 很高兴见到你
I'll see you later, Monica. Bye. It was good to see you.
再见，托尔 还是德克？
I'll see you later, Thor. I mean Dirk.
噢，特伦特？ 对不起，是特洛伊
Uh, I mean Trent. Sorry, Troy.
对不起，金头发
Whoop, sorry, Goldie.
施瑞德，你去哪了？ 我找你半小时了
Schrader, where you been? I've been calling you for half an hour.
又怎么了，哥们？ 我正忙
What the hell, man? I'm in the middle of rush.
我不管，哥们 我遇到麻烦了
I don't care, man. I got a situation goin' on.
这对我很重要 明白？
This is huge for me, all right?
- 你不要在这个时候出现 - 好，好，好
You can't be here right now. Okay, okay, okay.
还记得那次去偷我妈的避孕药？
Remember that time we had to steal my mom's birth control pills?
- 当然，于是莉齐出世了 - 这次比那还糟糕
Yeah, and then Lizzie was born. It's worse than that.
这些人从哪来的？
SCHRADER: Where did these people come from?
从那些乱糟糟的花名册 他们都无学可上
Oh, from the chaos catalog. They were going out of business.
- 出什么事了？ - 马上就告诉你
What is happening? I'll tell you what's happening.
上次让你做一个看上去合法的网站 但是不要功能化
I told you to make the website look legitimate, not functional.
嗨，你想骗你父亲 他可不是白痴
Hey, you wanted to fool your dad. And the guy's not an idiot.
同时，也是你提议加个“录取”选项
And, also, it was your idea to put "Acceptance is just one click away."
对，对，加一个选项 但是不能真的可以点
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Put it as one click away, you don't make it clickable.
噢，天啊，施瑞德，该死的
RORY: Oh, my... SCHRADER: Holy shit.
耶
Yeah.
他们都付了第一学期的学费？
They all paid first semester's tuition?
对，每人一万
Oh, yeah. 10,000 bucks apiece.
100张支票后我就没继续点
I stopped counting after the first 100 checks.
74万
That's $74,000,000.
100万，格伦
It's $1,000,000, Glen.
对，可流通的美金
Yeah. In human dollars.
好了，好了 我们该做点事情
Okay, okay, okay. We gotta do something.
嘿，别看我，问问某个发起人吧
Hey, don't look at me. Ask one of the founding fathers.
B?
HANDS: B?
我可没办法，哥们
This isn't my deal, man.
开始我就和你说这不是好主意
I told you this was a bad idea from the get-go.
对
True.
我们要开始大逃杀了
We could have a Battle Royale.
喔 那是什么？
Wow. What is that?
B，你该让这些人回去
B, you gotta tell these people to go home.
你是对的，哥们
You are absolutely right, my friend.
事情由我开始，就让我来结束吧
I started this, I'm gonna finish it.
谢谢
Thank you.
(STUDENTS CHATTERlNG)
上吧
Go.
嘿，格伦
Hey. Hey, Glen!
好了
All right.
(MlKE FEEDBACK)
(ALL EXCLAlMlNG)
对不起
Sorry. Sorry, sorry.
对不起，大家
Excuse me. I'm sorry, I'm sorry, everybody.
我能占用你们一点时间？
Can l-- Can I just get your attention for one minute?
好，我会在一分钟讲完
Um, yeah, I'll be taking questions in a minute.
请给我点时间，安静下来 好了
Just give me one second, please. Hold on. All right.
你是哪位？
Who the hell are you?
(STUDENTS ASSENTlNG)
啊哈
Ah-ah. Okay.
问的好 谢谢
That's a good question. Thank you.
我叫巴特比 你好
My name's Bartleby. Hello.
呃， 基恩斯 要说的是
Um, Gaines, for what it's worth.
呃，你们知道网站上说的
And, um, you know on the website how it said,
"录取只在弹指之间"？
"Acceptance is just one click away"?
还记得？
Do you remember that?
我们原本... 别动
We had intended... Hold on.
我们加上这句是因为... 噢，该死的
We added that because we were... Aw, shit.
算了，你..你想干什么？
Yeah, okay, what... I'm sorry. What--What--What do you want?
当我被这录取的时候
When I got accepted here,
我父母第一次说他们为我而骄傲
it was the first time my parents ever said they were proud of me!
(STUDENTS LAUGHlNG)
(STUDENT WHlSTLlNG)
(STUDENTS CHEERlNG WlLDLY)
很棒 很不错，哥们
That's cool. Um, that's cool, man.
好，举下手 多少人有申请其他学校？
Hey, uh, just show of hands, how many people applied to other colleges?
都有，好
Everybody. Uh, okay.
有多少人如愿以偿？
And how many of you got in to the other places you applied to?
没有人
Nobody.
没有人通过？
Nobody got in anywhere else?
你们知道吗，我也没有
And you know what? I didn't, either.
我也没有进入真正的大学
I didn't get into a real college.
真正的，好的大学
A really, really good college.
我知道被拒的感受
I know what it's like to be rejected. It sucks.
他们跟你说不
Rejection blows. Being said no to.
诸如，对不起，你还不够优秀
You know what, I'm sorry, you're just not quite good enough.
你没有足够的课外活动
You didn't have enough extracurriculars.
你网球玩的不够好
You didn't play enough tennis.
你的没有认真修学分 所以你还做的不够
You didn't study hard enough for your scores. So you're not gonna make it.
这都是百般挑剔
You know what? Screw that!
他在做什么？
(WHlSPERlNG) What's he doing?
我想他在预热
I think he's winging it.
难道我们就没有被接受的机会？
Shouldn't we all have the chance to be said yes to?
在南哈蒙 我们跟你说可以
At South Harmon, we say yes to you!
我们对你的愿望说可以
(ALL CHEERlNG) We say yes to your hopes.
对你的梦想说可以
We say yes to your dreams.
包容你的缺点 欢迎你们！
We say yes to your flaws! So welcome!
找个房子，找个朋友
Grab a room, grab a friend,
把握自己 我们不会插手
grab yourself, we don't give a shit.
欢迎来到南哈蒙理工学院
Welcome to South Harmon lnstitute of Technology!
噢，哥们
Oh, man.
欢迎来到S.H.I.T.！
And welcome to S.H.I.T.!
你！我爱你！
You! I love you!
(GROANS)
你在干什么？
SCHRADER: What are you doing?
你没意识到这有多蠢？
Do you realize how stupid this is?
你请他们来到一个根本不存在的学校
You invited everyone to a college that doesn't exist.
我，我说不出口 你看到他们的表情
I--I just couldn't do it, okay? You saw their faces.
他们四处碰壁
They got rejected from everywhere.
要是我再把他们拒了 会有多惨？
What--What kind of message does that send if I reject them from my college?
你没有学校！
You don't have a college!
嘿！书店在哪？
Hey, hey, hey, where's the bookstore?
我们可以从Amazon上买
Oh, we have a deal with Amazon.
有信用卡即可
You just buy 'em with a credit card.
何时选课？
When do we sign up for classes?
我们在扩专业 你会有的
Uh, we extended orientation. You're fine.
我们在哪吃饭？
Hey, man, where the heck do we eat around here?
格伦，300个披萨 发给他们
Uh, Glen, uh, 300 pizzas. Order them.
18个披萨袋 什么？不不，3个
18 pizza pockets. What? No, no, no. 3...
嘿，我该把学费交给谁？
Hey, who do I give my intuition money to?
谁？什么？ 我，我想
Who? What? Me, I guess.
我挑了块好布“钓”来的
I'm done fishing singles out of my G-string.
我现在是大学生喽！ 耶
I'm a college girl now! Aw, yeah.
噢
Wow.
B，你要办虚构的学校
Uh, B, hey, uh, you just started a fictional college.
噢，上帝. 好
Oh, God. Yeah, yeah, okay.
嘿，这里有游泳队吗？
Hey, do you guys have a swim team here?
有，这是汉兹·霍洛威 他是体育指导
Yes, you know what? This is Hands Holloway. He's the Athletic Director.
他会帮你了解任何事情 我现在没空
He can help you with anything you need to know. I can't do it right now.
谢谢 对不起
Thank you, though, thank you, I'm sorry.
- 你这家伙，现在该怎么做？ - 我需要一分钟来考虑
RORY: Uh, you guys, what are we gonna do now? I just need a minute to think.
什么？ 该死的！
What? What the... Holy shit!
嘿！嘿！住手！住手！
Hey! Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, Tex!
你们在做什么？
What the hell are you guys doing?
你什么意思？ 我们想让房子大一点
What do you mean? We're makin' the room bigger!
有道理 但这是我的房间
Yeah, Thorgeous, but this is my room.
这里谁管分房子？
Who's in charge of room assignments around here, anyway?
两位，这是罗莉
Guys, I'd like you to meet Rory.
她负责S.H.I.T.的房间分配
She is the resident S.H.I.T. room assignmenter.
她很乐意帮你们解决困难 对不对？
And she'll be more than happy to help you out with that. Okay?
好吧，我想...我可以带你们看房子
Okay, uh, l--I guess I'll show you your rooms.
- 跟我来 - 谢谢
Follow me. Thanks.
抱歉
Sorry about the wall.
没事 别担心这个，哥们
Oh, it's fine. Don't worry about it, man.
这事经常有 没问题
It happens all the time. No problem.
对了，我们有个实际的问题
Yeah, well, we actually do have a problem
你不知道如何管理学校
because you don't know how to run a college.
没事，这不是问题 没事
It's fine. It's okay. It's fine.
放松，睡会觉 明早就好了
We'll just relax, get some sleep, we'll regroup tomorrow morning.
明天会万事大吉
It will be totally calm.
(ROCK MUSlC PLAYlNG)
喂！懒汉们，太妹们
GLEN: Ahoy! Scallywags and scally-ladies.
好吧，B少爷，我跟你做下去
Okay, dude, B, I'm with you on this, I am.
但我们现在需要个计划
But we need a plan, dude. We need a plan now.
我明白 我...我在想
I know. I know. I--l--l-- I'm processing.
(EXCLAlMS)
你得加快了
You're gonna need to process faster.
(CELL PHONE RlNGlNG)
这是... 为什么... 去看看怎么回事
What is... Why are the... Find out what's going on.
- 喂？ - 哈，我的大学生
Yo! JACK: Ah, there's my college man.
你在干什么，孩子？
How you doin', kid?
爸，现在不是说话的时候
Dad, now is not the--the-- the best time to talk.
别挂，让你妈说两句
Hang on, let me get your mother.
- 我能用吗？ - 过来，说两句
Can I have this? HANDS: Come here, let me talk to you.
- 黛安，拿电话！ - 亲爱的，是你吗？
Diane, pick up! Honey! Is it you?
别大叫
Stop yellin' in the damn phone.
噢，很久没和你说话了
Oh, it feels like ages since we've spoken to you.
现在学校怎样？
How's school so far?
很好 一切进展都...
Oh, it's going great. It's going really...
嘿，这里有人订了两打小桶？
Hey, someone here order two dozen kegs?
那边戴帽子的老家伙 正在赌博的那个
The--The--The old guy with the hat, playing craps.
在说什么？
JACK: What the hell was that?
似乎在说关于两打桶的事情
Sounded like he said something about two dozen kegs.
巴特比， 你在喝酒？
Bartleby, are you experimenting with alcohol?
不不，他说的是两打鸡蛋，妈
BARTLEBY: Aw, no, no, no. He said two dozen eggs, Mom.
你听错了 两打鸡蛋
You misunderstood. Two dozen eggs.
干什么要这么久？
What took you so long?
我在那边建个酒窖
I've been building a thirst over there!
嘿，听着 我可不是花钱让你在那煎蛋卷
Hey, listen, I'm not paying for you to be making omelets up there.
告诉你正在上什么课？
JACK: Tell me what classes you're taking.
课？
Classes?
好，我正在学...
Uh, right. I'm taking...
(WHOOPlNG)
统计学
Statistics.
贸易
And, uh, business
解剖学
and anatomy.
- 解剖学？ - 解剖学？
JACK: Anatomy? DIANE: Anatomy?
谢谢
BOY: Thanks, dude.
巴特比，巴特比
JACK: Bartleby, Bartleby!
耶
Yeah!
(STATIC OVER PHONE)
嘿，我一直想上大学
Hey. I always wanted to go to college.
但想尽办法还是没成
Couldn't get in anywhere, though,
因为我以前在军队待过
'cause I was in the military.
哦 饮料管理
Oh. Beverage ops.
刚才看了下周围 发现了秘密活动
I was snooping around, saw something secretive.
我知道下面CIA会进来
Next thing I know ClA swoops in,
这是不是很复杂？
does this whole brain-scramble thing.
现在我什么都不记得
Now I can't remember anything.
那么我可以在这里有一席之地？
So do you have room at the college for me?
这学期已经开始了 对不起
You know what, we already started the semester, I'm sorry.
好吧
That's cool, man. Yeah.
只是，我受到《退伍军人法》保护
It's just l--I got my Gl Bill,
我可以提前支付4年学费
and I can pay you all four years in advance.
好吧，你通过了 耶！
Okay, you're in. (LAUGHlNG) Yeah!
耶，欢迎来到南哈蒙！
Yeah, welcome to South Harmon. Whoo-hoo!
(SPLASH)
进展如何？
How's the processing?
我得了解大学的模式
I just have to figure this whole college thing out.
在哈蒙，我们提供经过时间考验的
COUNSELOR: Here at Harmon College, we offer a highly structured,
高质量的课程编排来训练年轻人的思维
time-tested curriculum carefully designed to stimulate the young mind.
基恩斯先生，你在考虑转学？
So, Mr. Gaines, you're thinking about transferring?
没有
I don't know about transferring.
我的人生马上会有一些不可思议的变化
My life is kind of, like, a little weird right now.
我只是想知道
But I just kind of want to figure out
这里面的关系
what all this is all about.
对不起
(THUDDlNG) Sorry.
- 你要去哪个学校？ - 什么？
A-And what college are you attending right now? Sorry?
- 哪个大学... - 噢，就在那
The college that you're... (MUMBLlNG) Oh, it's down there. By the thing.
什么？
Pardon me?
我想出去走走是否可以？ 没问题
I'd like to look around, if that's okay. Uh, that's fine.
如果你喜欢的话
If that's what you'd like to do.
谢谢，那...那很高兴见到你
Thank you. It was-- It was, uh, it was great to meet you.
噢，对不起
(CLATTERlNG) Oh, shit. Sorry.
没关系，别管它们，随它们去
That's all right. No. You know what? Leave them, leave them alone.
别管了
Leave it, leave them alone.
出去自便，OK？
And go on and take your tour, okay?
单倍所得税除以薄弱环节
A single rate of income tax eliminates loopholes,
津贴和免税部分
allowances and exemptions
也会鼓励偿还
as well as encourages payments
通过使用理论上会
through use of low interest rates,
引起经济泡沫的
which theoretically would cause
低利率的方法
an economic boom.
现在如果你们想提及... 噢，对不起
Now if you would refer back... Aw, shit. I'm sorry.
因此理论上我说的...
So theoretically what I was saying was...
这家伙真烦
This guy's pretty boring.
别和我说话！ 这会在期中考试中出现
Don't talk to me, man! Right, this is gonna be on the midterm.
我的课程向来都是得A
And my whole life is riding on an A in this class.
# 周日早晨，当我醒来
# Sunday morning I'm waking up
这家伙... EBlTA！
This guy's... EBlTA!
什么？
What?
息税前利率和分期偿还（EBlTA）
Earnings Before lnterest, Taxes and Amortization.
# 从哪里开始？ 从哪里启程？ #
# Where do I start? Where do I begin? #
下午好，同学们
TEACHER: Good afternoon, students,
欢迎来到 第二课堂
and welcome, everyone in the spillover class.
这...这是什么？
What the-- What is this?
马上开始今天的演讲...
We'll begin today's lecture...
(MUMBLlNG)
好的，8点图书馆见
GlRL: Okay, great, yeah. I'll see you in the library at 8:00.
我会带上笔记 好，到时候见
And I'll bring my notes. MONlCA: Okay, see you then.
再见，莫妮卡
GlRL: Bye, Monica.
(STUDENTS CHATTERlNG)
莫妮卡，嘿
Monica. Hey.
巴特比，你在跟踪我还是？
Bartleby. Hey, what, are you stalking me or something?
跟踪多难听
Stalking's an ugly word.
- 我想这是一个分身 - 噢
I like to think of it more like obsessively shadowing. Oh.
我在考虑来这里 所以我来体验下上课
I'm thinking about going here, so I'm checking out the classes.
- 真的？ - 你喜欢所有的课程？
Really? Yeah. Do you like all your classes?
当然，我选了一大堆
Yeah. I mean, well, I'm taking a bunch of classes
不喜欢的课
that I don't really care about.
眼下就有一个 虽然我死也不愿意选
There was this one, though, that I was dying to take.
但我还死不了 你看，还算好
But, um, I ended up not being able to. But, you know, it's okay.
下面要上什么课？
What was that one that you wanted to take?
- 摄影 - 真的？很棒啊
Uh, ph-photography. It's... Really? That's cool.
对 问题在哪？
Yeah. What was the problem?
你看，先是摄影新闻课
Well, see, there's this, um, photojournalism class,
但他们说只针对新闻专业
but they said it's only for journalism majors.
后来是艺术摄影课
And then there's this art photography class,
他们只针对艺术专业
but they said it's for fine arts majors.
我的指导老师说最好都不报
So my advisor said it would be best not to take either one, or something,
因为有些摄影课
because certain photography classes
最后不提供学位
don't apply to a degree in photography.
噢，太没意思了
Wow, that makes, that makes no sense at all.
是啊，真对不起
I know. Um, but I'm really sorry.
我得走了 我的古罗马历史课要迟到了
I gotta go, I'm gonna be late for my Ancient Roman History class.
- 很高兴见到你，再见 - 好的，再见
It was good seeing you. Bye. Okay. Bye.
嘿，呃...
Hey, uh...
那就是所谓的大学？
BARTLEBY: I'm-- I'm just saying, I mean, is that what college is?
你原以为怎样？ 人类精神的复兴？
What were you expecting? A renaissance of the human spirit?
美国教育就是狗屎
American education is in the shitter.
知道为什么？
You know why?
因为人们忽略了最重要的规则
Because people forget the most important rule.
大学是服务行业
College is a service industry.
服务行业？
A service industry?
为大众服务 其他的方式都不对
As in "serve us," as opposed to the other way around.
看那边的孩子们
Look, you see all these kids out here?
他们花钱来这
They all paid to come here.
对 他们是为一种经历而花钱
Right. They all paid for an experience.
什么经历？
What kind of experience?
这就不知道了 我可不会读心术
The hell if I know. I'm not a goddamn mind reader.
或许我可以问他们
Well, maybe I should just ask them.
欢迎大家交流
Welcome to the conversation.
我想学什么？
What do I want to learn?
为什么问我？
Why are you asking me?
格伦，我问你是因为我预感到
Well, I'm asking you, Glen, because I have a hunch
以前没人问过你
that no one's ever really asked you that before. Yeah?
呃，我喜欢薄烤饼，苜蓿芽，柠檬水
Well, I like pancakes and alfalfa sprouts and lemonade.
好，我们要适当处理他的学费
Okay, you know what, let's appropriate the bulk of this man's tuition
以便学更多的厨房艺术
to learning more about the culinary arts.
- 啊？ - 食物
Huh? Food.
- 太好了 - 太好了
All right. All right.
罗莉，你呢？
Rory. What about you?
从托儿所开始 每一分钟的私人时间
Ever since nursery school, every single waking moment
甚至走路的时候都被干预
of every single day has been scheduled.
我想要什么？
So what do I want to do?
什么都不要
Nothing.
便宜，安静，美丽 我喜欢这些，助手，你呢？
Cheap, zen, beautiful. I like it. Hands, what about you?
夏营时我做了镇纸（压纸的工具）
Summer camp I made a paperweight and won Camp Nagachewy's
获得组里的雕刻大奖 第二天跑了4.6公里
coveted woodcarving award and next day,
一直以来都是橄榄球运动员的量
ran a 4.6 forty and it's been football ever since.
木雕，雕刻 喜欢动手
Mmm. Woodcarving, sculpting. Good, something with your hands.
那里面会有些东西
Well, there may be something in there.
你可以考虑下 然后告诉我，OK？
You can think about that, and then get back to me. All right?
施瑞德，你呢？ B，很高兴你会问我，其实
Schrader, what about you? Well, B, I'm glad you asked, actually.
由于我们在走向牢狱
'Cause since we're going to prison,
我想学怎样用牙刷切开腿骨
I'm gonna learn how to carve a shank out of my toothbrush.
哈哈，我会告诉你
Okay, ha-ha. I'll tell you something, though.
一直以来我们被传授如何学习
All our lives we've been told what to learn.
今天，我们反行其道
Well, today the tide is gonna turn, my friend.
因为我们今天要去问同学们
Because today we're gonna ask the customer.
- 我想学什么？ - 我想学什么？
What do I want to learn? What do I want to learn?
对学什么有兴趣？
What am I interested in studying?
- 啊？ - 什么？
Huh? What?
- 什么？ - 再说下
W-What? Come again.
- 好问题 - 不，再说下
That's a good question. No, really, come again.
我以为你会告诉我们
I thought you were supposed to tell us.
请再说下！
Please come again!
想见女孩们
I want to meet girls.
- 女孩 - 女孩
Girls. Girls.
- 女孩们！ - 呃，女孩
Some girls! Uh, girls.
摇滚！
I wanna rock!
(CHUCKLlNG)
还有轮滑
You know, and roll.
呃，如你所说的
Well, as you can probably tell at this point,
我最想学怎样让事物慢下来
is that I really want to learn how to slow things down.
- 更快 - 更绿
More speed. More vert.
关于衣服的，明白？
Maybe something with clothes, you know?
穿上去，脱下来
Putting them on, taking them off.
我喜欢这样 想不想看？
I'm really good at that part. You wanna see?
我想学意念控制
I want to learn how to blow shit up with my mind.
不错，写到黑板上
Okay. Well, write it on the board.
去吧
Go ahead.
好了，谢谢
Okay, thanks. Okay.
好了 谢谢，笑纳
All right. Thank you, smiley.
交易愉快
Pleasure doing business with you.
好了，兄弟
Yeah, buddy.
(HOLIDAY PLAYlNG)
税？和你们说那都是胡扯
Taxes? I'll tell you about that nonsense.
假如你有钱 政府会保护你
If you're rich, the government'll protect
创造和拿走的每分钱
every buck you make and every shit you take.
凯迪，给你个活
Kiki Dee. Got a job for you, kid.
新的校服和校标 由你负责
New school colors and logo. You're in charge.
- 真的吗？ - 别搞砸了
Really? Don't screw it up.
绝对放心 我不会搞砸任何...
I won't screw it up, l--I won't screw anything...
#战斗今天失利
#...war today
# 我向梦想乞求 这不是
# I beg to dream and differ
# 空洞的谎言
# From the hollow lies
# 这是我们余生的黎明
# This is the dawning
# Of the rest of our lives
# 在假日
# On holiday
# 传来不合拍的鼓点
# Hear the drum pounding out of time
你是谁？
What are you?
# 反对者们已过线
# Another protester has crossed the line
# 嘿！
# Hey!
# 去寻找对方的金钱
# To find the money's on the other side
# 在假日
# On holiday
# 嘿！
# Hey!
# 我向梦想乞求 这不是空洞的谎言
# I beg to dream and differ from the hollow lies
# 这是我们余生的黎明
# This is the dawning
# Of the rest of our lives
# 在假日
# On holiday
医疗保险，可笑 他们不会给
Health insurance, my ass. They don't pay for shit!
你周五呕吐 他们只会负责周一到周四的
You get sick on a Friday, they only pay for Monday through Thursday.
你去A医生那看病 但他们只给B医生钱
You go to Dr. A, they only pay for Dr. B.
你鸡鸡坏了 他们只修复阴道
You break your penis, they only fix vaginas.
介意加我一个？
You mind if I join you?
太爽了 谢谢，太棒了
Ah, cool. Awesome. Thank you, that was great!
下次见，再见
I'll see you guys later. Okay, bye.
这不错，呃...
That's pretty, uh...
当然啊
I know, right?
这是关于非洲生殖能力的雕刻
That's African fertility sculpture.
不错，真不错
It's beautiful. It's beautiful.
# 胜利万岁！ 向着总统，哥们
# Sieg Heil to the president gas, man
木头和我说话
The wood speaks to me.
和你说？
The wood speaks to you?
# 把艾菲尔铁塔研碎
# Pulverize the Eiffel towers
# 谁批评你的政府
# Who criticize your government
女士们先生们 新S.H.I.T.排演
Ladies and gentlemen, the new S.H.I.T. Iine.
(ALL CHEERlNG)
# 这不是我要走的路
# Is not a way that's meant for me
# 只是因为
#Just cause
谢谢
Thank you.
#只是因为
#Just cause #
学习是什么？ 就是集中注意力
UNCLE BEN: What is learning? It's paying attention!
向我们称为生活的大舞台 张开你自己
It's opening yourself up to this great big ball of shit that we call life!
什么是最坏的事情？ 你屁股被咬
And what's the worst thing that can happen? You get bit in the ass!
让我告诉你们 我的屁股像汉堡上的肉
Well, let me tell you, my ass looks like hamburger meat,
但我仍可坐下
but I can still sit down!
(ALL CHEERlNG)
难以置信这就是我们要上的课
I can't believe this is a class.
哇
BOYS: Yeah.
看我做的
Look what I did.
噢，这是什么？
Ugh. What are those?
我称之“幽谷”
I call 'em GlenWads.
每一口都有不同的风味 来一个
They contain every delicious flavor in every single bite. Try one.
不想骗你 这很恶心
I'm not gonna lie to you. They look disgusting.
它会给你独一无二的风味 你吃了肯定会爽
This shit will get you high on flavor alone.
格伦，我喜欢这个大杂烩
Glen, I love your Wads. Hmm.
格伦
Glen.
这是最... 确切说是我吃过的最难以置信的
This is like the most... Literally the most incredible thing I've ever eaten.
小心，哥们
Heads up, bro.
啊
Whoa.
很容易咽 格伦
And it's so easy to swallow. Mmm. Wow, Glen.
- 让下，哥们 - 当然
Uh, excuse me. Thanks, buddy. Sure.
嘿，怎么了？ 嘿
Hey, how's it going? Hey.
有什么可以帮忙？
Can I help you with something?
你不是那个家伙？
Aren't you that guy?
我不这样认为
No, I don't think so.
- 你不是？ - 不是什么？
You're not? I'm not what?
我看你行色匆匆的，你在这做什么？
I saw you at rush. What are you doing here?
我吃东西，哥们 你在这做什么？
I'm eating a Wad, man. What are you doing here?
等等，让我猜
Wait--wait, let me guess.
你想让我在 禁止少数派到你俱乐部的
You want me to sign your petition
倡议书上签名，对不对？
banning minorities from your yacht club. No?
我是会长 确切说是
I am the chairman, actually,
哈蒙学院学生社区推广委员会
of the Student Community Outreach Committee at Harmon College.
啊！那是我下面要猜的
Ah! That was my next guess. My next guess.
听起来不错
That sounds very important.
- 本来就是 - 所以我这么说
As a matter of fact, it is! That's why I said it.
哈蒙想买这里
And Harmon wants to buy this property,
你知道谁是产权所有者？
so do you know where I could find the lease holder?
我知道
I do.
能告诉我吗？
Well, could you tell me?
当然可以
Oh, yeah, I could. I could, Gunther.
好 准备和我说了?
Okay, well, are you going to tell me?
不不 我想和你说的是
No. I'm not gonna tell you. I will tell you this.
这里的所有者对转手没有兴趣
The lease holder's not interested in relocating at any point.
谢谢你来问这些 祝你愉快
So thanks for asking, and have a good day.
好好玩你主持的游戏 再见
And enjoy the game show that you host. Bye-bye.
噢，小心
Oh, look out.
打开
Open it.
谢谢光临
Ah. Thank you for coming by.
祝你愉快 我要继续享受美食了
Have a good day. I'm gonna go enjoy my Wad.
(GRUNTlNG)
嘿！这是什么鬼地方？
Hey! What the hell is this place?
曾经最棒的南哈蒙理工学院
South Harmon lnstitute of Technology. The best college ever.
是要考验我吗？
Is this a test?
嘿，杂碎
STUDENT: Hey, Sperminator.
南哈蒙？
South Harmon?
敲门
GWYNN: Knock, knock.
嘿，格温
Oh, hey, Gwynn.
嘿，一个人在做什么？
Hey. Hey, what are you doing up here all by your lonesome?
整晚都看不到你
You know, you're missing the whole party.
有没有听过南哈蒙理工学院？
Hey, have you ever heard of the South Harmon lnstitute of Technology?
没有，哪来的？
No. How come?
不知道
No reason.
嘿，托盘子的
CHAMBERS: Hey, pledge.
你好，自由骑士
Hello, knights of freedom.
杂碎，你知道为什么打扮成这样？
Sperman, do you know why you're dressed like this?
这是手足情深的标志
Because it's required for brotherhood.
喝了它 好
Drink this. Okay.
不，等等
No, wait.
来吧
There you go.
加的好，哥们
Good addition, sir.
(FRAT BOYS LAUGHlNG)
霍伊特，你在干什么？
Hey, Hoyt. Hey, what are you doin'?
啊哦，霍伊特
Oh-oh. Hoyt.
莫妮卡，等等，该死！
HOYT: Monica. Hold on. Shit!
(DOOR SLAMMlNG)
哈蒙大道，该死 跟你说些事
UNCLE BEN: Harmon Gateway, my ass. Let me tell you something.
那是混球们的集体力量 会影响全美
That's the kind of group-think mob mentality that's dumbing down America
让你们的脑袋 经过马桶洗礼
and flushing your brains down the toilet.
B！我们有麻烦了
B! We have a problem.
维珍黛可利
Virgin daiquiri.
放点酸橙，橡皮头
And easy on the lime there, Eraserhead.
马上就好
Comin' right up.
莉齐 你在这做什么？
Lizzie. What are you doing here?
难道我不能到处走走 来看看我的大学生哥哥？
You mean I can't swing by and visit my big brother at college?
你在上大学，是吗？
You are in college, aren't you?
什么意思？
What is that supposed to mean?
算了吧，巴特比
Come on, Bartleby. The jig's up.
我正准备告诉爸妈
I'm telling Mom and Dad.
听好，你想要什么？
Uh, listen, w-w-what do you want?
两万块
$20,000.
什么？没门 疯了，算了吧
What? No way! That's insane. Come on.
我没空和你玩游戏
I'm not gonna play your little game.
我不会给你一分钱
I'm not gonna give you a cent.
你有多喜欢？ 你很喜欢吗？
How do you like that? How do you like them apples, huh?
真幸运，爸妈都在快捷拨号组
Fortunately, Mom and Dad are on speed dial.
我让他们来接我
Oh. I'll ask them to pick me up here.
好吧，你要给他们电话 铃响了
Okay, you're gonna call Mom and Dad, sure. Ringing.
绝对是欺诈
You are bluffing with the best.
真象，虽然 我必须给你
You're very good, though. I gotta give it to you.
你好，妈妈 好了，住手
Hi, Mom. Okay, stop it.
所有你想的 不关钱的事
Anything you want, not money-related.
你的劲爆单脚踏板车 没问题
Your Razor scooter. Done.
和一个假身份证 不！这不行
And a fake lD. No! That's ridiculous.
我可不想让你喝酒
I'm not gonna let you drink.
就想要这些，笨蛋
It's so I can vote, dumbass.
噢，成交
Oh. Okay, deal.
你要滑板车去投票？
You need a Razor scooter to vote?
什么意思？ 他们是学院？
What do you mean, they're a college?
他们自称南哈蒙理工学院
They're called the South Harmon lnstitute of Technology.
南哈蒙理工学院？
The South Harmon lnstitute of Technology?
这算什么？ 玩笑？
What is this, some kind of joke?
不，我不这样认为
No, I don't think it is, sir.
安布罗斯先生
Mr. Ambrose, that is the one building
那个建筑夹在我和卡尔加里之间
standing between me and the Van Horne Gateway.
我不知道怎么和你说，先生
Well, I don't know what to tell you, sir.
告诉我你不再天真
Tell me that you're not that naive.
大学不是在一夜之间跳出来的
Colleges don't just spring up out of the ground overnight.
你说的，先生
You're right. You're right, sir.
我知道我说得对！
I know I'm right!
别担心，我会找个办法把他们赶走
All right, don't worry. I'll-- I'll figure a way to get them out of there.
多好的主意 安布罗斯先生
What an excellent idea, Mr. Ambrose.
这个主意会帮你进法学院
That's the kind of thinking that will get you into law school.
来喽！
DWAYNE: Coming through!
喔！
Ow!
(CHATTERlNG)
你在这做什么？
Hey, what are you doing here?
为照相机的事来谢谢你
I just came to thank you so much for my camera, B.
太感谢你了，很棒
It was so sweet, thank you.
别客气，别老惦记这些
Come on. Please, I figured, who needs a life's savings, right?
我花了好大功夫才找到这儿
Actually, I had a really hard time finding this place.
电话本里没有你们
You--You guys aren't listed in the phone book,
而且几乎没人知道这儿
and nobody really seems to know about you guys.
对对，我们保密的很好
Yeah, yeah, we're-- we're a pretty well-kept secret.
好了，让我带你转转
Well, let me-- let me show you the rest of the place.
好啊
Sure. Really?
当然了
Yeah, of course. Okay.
太好了
Great. Great.
- 走吧 - 好
Let's, let's go. All right.
- 两杯火山熔岩 - 谢谢
Two lava flows. Thank you.
声音小点 大家都在玩
And keep your voice down. People are playing.
- 喔，谢谢 - 好的，谢谢
Okay. Thanks, buddy. Mmm. Oh, okay. Thank you.
- 他做的不错 - 是啊
He makes a mean drink. Yeah. It's great.
你好
(CELL PHONE RlNGlNG) All right. Hello.
饮料怎样？
How do you like your drink?
非常棒，格伦 谢谢
Yeah, it's really good, Glen. Thanks.
她呢？
Does she like hers?
很棒 对，她...
Uh, yeah. Yeah, yeah, she...
- 对，很不错 - 谢谢
Yeah, it's great. Thank you.
- 好了，谢谢 - 很好，哥们
Okay, great, thanks. Okay, pal. Okay.
噢，格伦
Ah, Glen.
这是你们的课程指南？
Wait. So this is your course guide?
对，这是个新花样
Yeah, this is a new pilot program.
领导希望我们建设自己的教室
See, the administration wanted us to create our own classes,
所以我们把它们写在黑板上
so we just, uh, write 'em on the board.
- 真的？ - 对
Really? Yeah.
太棒了，B
Wow, that's so cool, B.
- 要不你也选个？ - 不不
Hey, why don't you sign up for one? No, no.
- 来吧，选一个 - 不不，巴特比
Come on. Sign up for one. No. No, Bartleby, no.
- 没什么的 - 真的？
It-- It's painless. I insist. Oh, really?
就算你不选 站在上面也很好玩
Even if you don't sign up for one you'll go on a fun ride.
好吧
Okay.
看到喜欢的就让我停下
Just stop me when you see something that you like.
好，我喜欢这个 “男人：相对弱的性别”
Okay. Oh, I like this one. "Men: The Weaker Sex."
给我只笔 噢
Give me a pen. (CHUCKLES) Oh.
B，“该死的236“可不象课
B, there can't honestly be a class called "Bullshitting 236."
堕落的塞维·蔡斯呢？
What about "The Decline and Fall of Chevy Chase"?
很多人都要选这门课
There's a wait list for that one.
(EXPLOSlON)
(STUDENTS EXCLAlM)
什么？
What?
你没事吧？
Are--Are you okay?
什么？
(SHOUTlNG) What?
出什么事了？
What the hell happened?
香料爆炸
An explosion of flavor!
我正在处理些易燃的香料
I'm working with some very unstable herbs!
等等，你是说
MONlCA: Wait, wait, wait. So you're telling me
这没有考试或论文
that there are no tests, or essays,
要求阅读或者其他类似的？
or required reading, or any of that nonsense?
是的，从没有
That's what I'm sayin'. Wow. Ever?
绝对没有
Yeah. Never ever.
还是问问我的香肠吧，太神奇了
SCHRADER: Ask me about my wiener! That's amazing.
太棒了
Yeah, it's pretty cool.
噢，不
BARTLEBY: Oh, no.
还是问问我的香肠！
Ask me about my wiener!
(GlRL CHUCKLES)
这是...
(CHUCKLES) What the...
还是问问我的香肠吧！
Ask me about my wiener!
施瑞德？
Schrader?
哦 B，你好
SCHRADER: Oh, hey, B. Hi.
莫妮卡
And Monica.
为什么穿成这样？
Hey. Why--Why are you wearing this?
兄弟会里每个人都穿成这样
Every single brother in my fraternity has worn this suit.
詹姆斯总统穿这个就像绅士
President James Garfield wore this suit like a gentleman.
哦，知道后来怎么了？
Oh, yeah, and look what happened to him.
后来他被查尔斯刺杀了
He got assassinated by Charles Guiteau.
别问我怎么知道
Don't ask me how I know that.
帮个忙 快问候我的香肠
Do me a favor, ask me about my wiener really quickly.
施瑞德，不
Schrader, no.
我的朋友正看着我
Guys, my brothers could be watching me right now.
快问我
Just ask me about my wiener, please.
为什么做这些？ 你什么意思？
Why are you doing this? What do you mean?
快点... 这...
Come on. You're... This...
你在羞辱你自己，兄弟
You're humiliating yourself, buddy.
你懂什么，B 别捣乱
You know what, B. Don't mess with me!
这是我一生最快乐的时候
These are the happiest times of my life, all right?
- 施瑞德 - 我很开心
Schrader. I'm so happy, I'm the happiest.
很开心！
I'm happy!
嘿！问候我的香肠
Hey! Ask me about my wiener!
S.H.I. T.校刊 热卖
S.H.I. T. Rag. Hot off the presses.
你的，B. 谢谢
Here you go, B. BARTLEBY: Thanks, Boner.
S.H.I.T.校刊？
The S.H.I. T. Rag?
是啊，每个学校都有自己的校报
Yeah, come on, every school's gotta have a paper.
有块特稿 是关于不要相信你读的任何事情
There's a great op-ed piece in there about not believing everything you read.
很煽情啊
It's really provocative.
听我话，快关了吧
As your de facto consigliere my advice to you is to shut this down immediately.
别担心
And my advice to you is to stop worrying
在你完蛋之前
before you spontaneously combust.
对，但你不能只做这个
Yes, but you can't just do this.
真正的大学
To be a real college,
必须经过适当的法律途径
you have to go through the appropriate legal channels.
需要公众认可
You need to be accredited.
你能帮上忙吗
Well, yeah, could you take care of that?
B. 看起来不错.伙计
Hey, B. Pancho, looking good, pal.
那是什么？ 拍我屁股
Who's that? GLEN: Spank me.
那是吉祥物
That's, uh, the mascot.
吉祥物？ 对
Oh, it's the mascot? Yeah.
三明治？ 对
A sandwich? Yes.
你们是S.H.I.T.三明治？ 对
You're the S.H.I.T. Sandwiches? Yes, we are.
你有点过火了
You are taking this way too far.
为什么？ 我也不知道
How so? Oh, I don't know, man.
可能是这个池子 或者半根管子
Maybe it's the pool, or the half-pipe.
那些不在预算 我会再投入
That's not in the budget. I'm re-investing in their education.
那些是南哈蒙的基石
Those are South Harmon cornerstones there.
对，但你没注意分区制要求
Yes, but you're overlooking zoning requirements,
噪声控制，保险问题
noise permits, there are insurance issues.
保险？ 那会怎样？
Come on. Insurance? What's gonna happen?
(MOTORCYCLE REVVlNG)
(WHOOPlNG)
噢，该死
Oh, shit.
(ALL CHEERlNG)
噢
Wow.
耶
WAYNE: Yeah!
该死
Aw, shit.
再来一次 没开盖子
We gotta do it again, dudes. Left the lens cap on.
不要！ 笨蛋！
FEMALE STUDENT: No, you didn't! Damn!
你是对的 走的太远了
You know what? You're absolutely right. This has gone way too far.
我们要赶紧做些什么
And I think we need to do something about it ASAP.
- 谢谢 - 谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
(BAND PLAYlNG LOUD ROCK MUSlC)
# 二十公里以外，你是团气体
# Twenty miles from nowhere you're outta gas
# 但你一直抬着头
# But you're keeping your head up
# 最后，我在神秘城堡里活下
# Well, I'm alive in the mystical tower at last
# 但你一直抬着头
# But you're keeping your head up
怎么样？
Is this great or is this great?
很棒 但我得走了
It's pretty cool, man, but I gotta go.
“咆哮20秒”是B.K.E今年最大的聚会
The Roaring '20s is B.K.E's biggest party of the year.
我们要玩些另类的
And we're recreating the scene from The Untouchables
罗伊，象德尼罗一样
where Roy, as Bobby De Niro,
用棒球打我的头
crushes my skull with a baseball bat.
真了不起
Wow, what an incredible honor.
能给拷贝本签名吗？
Could you sign a copy of your book for me?
在易趣买的 他们在易趣卖我的书？
I got it on eBay. They sell my shit on eBay?
- 你写书？ - 对
You wrote a book? Yeah.
关于以前喝酒的
But that was back when I was drinking.
格伦，你不能让我们排队等着
Come on, Glen, you can't keep stringing us along.
选谁？
Which one of us is it going to be?
# 你一直抬着头，我明白你
# You're keeping your head up I know you
# 你一直抬着头，不让低下 #
# You're keeping your head from falling down #
(ALL CHEERlNG)
安静！安静！安静！
Quiet, quiet, quiet! Quiet, shh!
女士们，先生们 让我们欢迎伟大的头
Ladies and gentlemen, let's give it up for your fearless leader,
巴特比 上来，哥们
Bartleby Gaines. Come on up here, buddy!
伙计
Aw, man.
谢谢 上来
Thanks. Thank you. Get up here!
上来！ 我想你明白！
Come on up! I know you know this one!
马上上来！ 上吧
Go. Go up there right now. Go, man, go!
你怎么做的 耶！就是你
How you doin'? Yeah! You the man.
# 嘿，哦，一起出发
#Hey, ho, let's go
# Hey, ho, let's go
# 嘿，哦，一起出发
# 他们排成直线
# They're forming in a straight line
# 穿过狂风
# They're going through a tight wind
# 孩子们失去方向
# The kids are losing their minds
# 闪电奇袭！
# Blitzkrieg bop!
我就要开始了
I'm going to have that.
闭嘴
Shut up.
看，人都去哪了？
Look, where the hell is everybody at?
你！
You! Hey.
你怎么了？
Hey. How are you?
上帝，人都去哪了？
Aw, God, look, where the hell is everybody?
这是今年最大的聚会
HOYT: This is the biggest party of the year, guys.
乐队！
Band, hey!
来点音乐吧？
Ah, you want to start playing some music, please?
- 嘿 - 霍伊特
Hey. GWYNN: Hoyt, hey.
似乎有更大的聚会
There's, like, some big party down the hill.
啊，那是...
Oh, that son of a...
# 嘿，哦，一起出发
# Hey, ho, let's go
# 嘿，哦，一起出发 #
# Hey, ho, let's go #
(ALL CHEERlNG)
(WHOOPlNG)
(DRUMMER PLAYlNG)
嘿！B，太棒了
Hey! B, oh, my gosh, that was fantastic.
上帝，你看到了 多不好意思
Aw, my God, you saw that. I'm embarrassed.
我也不知道自己怎么了
I don't know what happened to me.
他们让我疯狂，我想 是乔伊·雷蒙的附体吧
Someone possessed me, and-- and it was the spirit of Johnny Ramone, I think.
B，还有什么绝活？
B, is there anything that you're not incredibly amazing at?
问的好
Yeah, it's funny you should ask.
想说少的确很难
There are very few things I'm not very good at.
在我头顶上 还有洞穴探险和心灵遥感
Off the top of my head I can think of spelunking, uh, telekinesis,
失恋了不会哭
not crying at the end of My Girl.
就在我面前 还有奶制品
It gets me. And dairy products.
哪个好， 因为你知道今晚我真的
Which is good, because you know I'm not really in the mood
不想吃奶制品
for any dairy products tonight.
看看还能给你什么
Well, let's see if we can get you something else then.
- 看看吧 - 好
Let's see. All right.
- 这是我的...噢 - 噢
This is my... Oh! MONlCA: Ooh!
没事 我老是忘了开门
I'm okay, I'm okay. I keep forgetting this opens out.
经常这样 我要慢慢习惯
It happens all the time, I gotta get used to it.
噢，不
(LAUGHlNG) Oh, no.
这是
And this is
Mi casa（西班牙语：我的家）
Mi casa.
巴特比，天哪 太棒了
Bartleby, uh, oh, my God, this is amazing!
呃？还不错
Huh? It's fine.
我想说，我喜欢这样 简单而多功能
I mean, I like it 'cause it's simple, and functional.
有个好的工作地方 可以集中注意力
Provides a good safe workspace for me to focus on my studies.
(POP MUSIC PLAYING ON STEREO)
B，这太棒了 简单却很棒
B, this is so cheesy, in the greatest way.
声控迪斯科舞厅可不简单
There is nothing cheesy about a clap-on disco ball.
(CLAPS)
也许有一点
Maybe it's a little bit much.
孩提时我就想这样
I've wanted one since I was a kid, though.
等等，你们这每个人的房间都这么有意思？
Wait, is everybody's room at South Harmon this incredible?
在南哈蒙，你可以自己设计
Well, at South Harmon you're free
自己的房子，明白？
to kind of design your own rooms, you know?
不管你怎样想 不管你...
Whatever you're thinking, whatever you're...
我在想一个声控迪斯科舞台
And I was thinking clap-on disco ball.
喝点什么？ 要什么？
How about that drink? Can I get you a drink?
- 我确实想喝点什么 - 好的
I would love a drink. All right.
(MUSIC PLAYING ON STEREO)
- 啊，真对 - 啊
Ah, touché. Ahh.
# 嘿，嘿，嘿
# Hey, hey, hey
# 别忘记我
# Don't you forget about me
# 告诉我你的困难和疑惑
# Tell me your troubles and doubts
# 告诉我你所想
# Give me everything inside and out
# 爱情是奇怪的，在黑暗中如此真实
# Love's strange so real in the dark
# 我们所做的事情
# Type of thing that we're working on
# 会渐变而让我们分离
# Slow change may pull us apart
这个聚会很过瘾
This party's off the hook!
嘿嘿，闭嘴
Hey, hey, hey, shut up!
那个混蛋在哪？
All right. Where is that asshole?
巴特比，那是七年级的事了
Co-Come on, Bartleby, that was 7th grade.
非常正确，正是我要说的
Yeah, exactly, that was my point.
- 好，我会让你知道的 - 现在
Well, I will have you know... Oh, now,
现在我不能回到过去 但你可以回头
now I can't go back to your past, but you can go back to mine.
克里斯蒂娜的造型做的不错，谢谢你
That Christina Aguilera look did very well for me, thank you very much.
你做的很棒 你做的很棒，我知道
Yeah, you did great, you did great. I know.
我记得你和皮特 在朱莉的地下室的事情
I remember you making out with Pete Goochman in Julie Posner's basement.
你参加了那个聚会？
You were at that party?
即使我不在 我也会知道
Oh, even if I wasn't there, I would have known about it.
它上了学校头条
It made headline news at school.
那天对我一生来说有些改变
And--And--And that day something happened in my life
我以为不会发生
that I never thought would happen.
我开始嫉妒皮特
I became envious of Pete "The Gooch" Goochman.
从没想到这会发生
Never thought it would happen.
但我就像是，“他要和莫妮卡约会了！”
But I was like, "He got to make out with Monica Moreland."
如果你很想在地下室亲我，为什么不？
Well, if you wanted to kiss me so bad in the basement, why didn't you?
除非古奇让我去
Well, 'cause the Gooch beat me to it,
我有点害羞 还有...
and I was a little shy, and, uh...
你现在想亲我？
Well, you want to kiss me now, don't you?
你像卡里·西蒙
You look like Carly Simon!
如果我可以说个偶像 那会是卡里·西蒙
If I could bang one woman in the world it'd be Carly Simon,
你很像她！
and you look like her!
有趣吗？
Are you having fun?
很有趣
I'm having so much fun.
我们去找他
HOYT: Let's go find him. Oh!
噢！该死 噢！该死
Oh, shit, oh, shit, oh, shit, oh, shit.
(CELL PHONE BEEPlNG)
对不起，稍等
Sorry. One sec.
该死，有麻烦
Oh, shit. Uh, I got a situation.
- 跟我来 - 好
Come, come with me. Okay.
#...进入你的心
#...into your heart
# 宝贝 宝贝 宝贝
# Baby, baby, baby
嘿，看见施瑞德没？
Hey, have you seen Schrader?
对不起
Excuse me.
该死
Shit.
莫妮卡？ 你在这做什么？
Monica? What are you doing here?
哦，来拿转学申请
Oh, you know, just picking up my application for transfer.
你现在和这家伙在一起？
You're telling me that you're with this guy now?
其实，霍伊特
Actually, Hoyt, um,
这和你无关
I'm telling you it's none of your business.
- 和我无关？ - 对
It's none of my business? Yeah.
噢，真突然！
Oh, snap!
霍伊特，让我来介绍个老朋友
Hey, Hoyt, let me introduce you to an old friend of mine.
“拒绝”这个词才是真的婊子
The word "rejection." She can be a real bitch.
但你不必给她迷药
But you don't have to give her roofies.
你不会喜欢她
So you're not gonna like her. Ooh.
你想我给你笑料？
You want me to give you something funny to laugh about?
你的意思是 会比你下面发酒疯还有趣？
You mean something funnier than your future alcohol abuse?
大逃杀！
Battle Royale!
该死 我们走
Uh, shit. FRAT BOY: Let's go, guys.
好吧 我们离开这
All right, come on, guys. Let's get out of here.
莫妮卡，你知道怎样挑选 对吧？
Wow, Monica, you really know how to pick 'em, don't you?
好好和这些白痴玩吧！
Have fun with these idiots!
再见 再见
Bye-bye. Bye.
谢谢你的到来
Thank you for comin'.
大家伙接着爽吧，来吧！
Guys, let's get the music back up! Come on!
# 嘿，嘿，嘿，嘿
# Hey, hey, hey, hey
# 不要忘记我
# Don't you forget about me
# 我会孤单
# I'll be alone
# 跳吧你会明白的宝贝
# Dancing and you know it baby
# 难道你...
(FIRE ALARM RINGING) # Don't you...
湿衣派对！
Wet T-shirt party!
(ALL CHEERlNG)
# 难道忘了我
# Don't you forget about me
# 告诉我你的麻烦和疑惑
# Tell me your troubles and doubts
# 给我每一部分
(WHOOPlNG) # Giving me everything inside and out
# 爱很奇怪，黑暗中如此真实
# Love's strange so real in the dark #
(KNOCKlNG ON DOOR)
爸？妈？
Mom? Dad?
- 格温 - 在这
Gwynn. Hi, there.
在这做什么？
What are you doing here?
我是你的保镖
I'm your escort.
加入之夜，大家伙
Induction night, big guy.
B.K.E., B.K.E. 手足之情，你和我！
B.K.E., B.K.E., brotherhood, brotherhood, you and me!
B.K.E., B.K.E. 手足之情 手足之情，你和我！
(WHOOPlNG) B.K.E., B.K.E. brotherhood, brotherhood, you and me!
谢尔曼·施瑞德 太激动了！
Sherman Schrader, you rock!
天！你们也是！
Aw, no! You guys rock!
准备加入兄弟会吧！ 你这家伙！
Get ready to be inducted into the brotherhood, you winner!
耶！我想要你们有的一切
Yes! I want it! I want everything you guys have. Whoo!
我要淡紫色体恤 我要舌帽
I want lilac shirts! I want visors
边上微翘，上发胶后露出来
kind of tilted to the side, with hair gel coming out of it.
我要和这样的女孩做爱！
I want to have sex with girls that look like this!
你可以！ 我知道！
You rock! I know I do!
- 你可以 - 你可以
You do, yeah, you do.
现在有发胶吗？ 还是要我自己买？
SCHRADER: Do I get hair gel now, or do I have to go and buy my own?
你问到什么没？
Did you crack him?
没
No.
我们会的
We'll crack him.
谢尔曼，你知道兄弟会有多久了?
Sherman, do you know how long that this fraternity has survived?
知道
Yes, sir.
神圣的153年
153 majestic years, sir.
很对，因为它有神圣的会规
That is correct. Because it's based on the most sacred principle
相互坦白
that brothers can share.
信任
Trust.
真诚 我要开问了
And seriously, bro, I'm-- I'm beginning to question
看你是否可信任
whether or not I can trust you.
因为你曾经和那些疯子在一起
'Cause we know you been hanging out with those freaks down at the loony bin.
所以有必要考验你的忠诚
So with your allegiance being called into question,
只问一个问题
I just wanted to ask you just one thing.
板子
Paddle.
- 其实不是问题！ - 闭嘴！
That's actually not a question. Shut up!
你跟他们
Are you with them
还是跟我们？
or are you with us?
很好的聚会
Decent party.
# 心跳 不错
# Heartbeat Not bad.
# 心跳
# Heartbeat
好的，我会给你象样的
Okay, I'll give you decent.
# 不用烦心打包
# Don't bother to pack your bags
# 或者你的面具
# Or your mask
# 我们去的地方不需要这些
# We won't need them where we're going
施瑞德在哪？ 他应该在这儿
(BURPS) Hey, where is Schrader? He should be here for this.
不知道，好多天没见了
I don't know. I haven't seen him in a couple of days.
希望没什么病吧
I hope he's not sick.
好了，快点，快点 大家齐喊茄子！
Okay. Quick, quick, quick, everybody say "Cheers"!
好了，快点 来这
Hey, "quick, quick, quick," get up in here.
不 来吧！
No. BARTLEBY: Oh, yes.
对对，来吧 好
Yes, yes, yes. Come over here. Okay.
辉煌时刻就要来了
Gotta up the gorgeous quotient.
好了，准备
Okay. Get ready and now.
茄子！
ALL: Cheers!
施瑞德
BARTLEBY: Schrader.
施瑞德，快开门
Schrader, come on, open up.
你...
What are you...
你怎么了？
What the hell happened to you?
没什么，在B.K.E.家庭仪式上粘的
Nothing. Just a little ritual bonding over at the B.K.E. House.
什么？ 你说什么？
What? What are you talking about?
他们踢我屁股 直到我交代了南哈蒙的一切
They kicked my ass, until I told them all about South Harmon.
该死
Oh, shit.
他们拿走了我的笔记本电脑 邮箱地址，所有的东西
They took my laptop, the mailing list, everything.
该死的，对不起
Shit. Man, I'm sorry.
我只想经历下大学生活
All I ever wanted was a run-of-the-mill college experience.
我不想，明白？ 我不能那样
But not me, right? I can't have that.
我不想
Not me!
我不想到头来被开除
'Cause I'm too busy getting the shit kicked out of me
成为骗子的帮凶
and being an accomplice to fraud!
这些大学经历
BARTLEBY: Does the run-of-the-mill college experience
包括失去你的尊严？
include stripping you of your dignity?
整天羞辱你 让你穿的象热狗？
Totally humiliating you, making you wear a--a--a frigging hot dog suit?
- 这是传统 - 传统？
It's a tradition. A tradition?
- 对 - 我倒是有个传统
Yes. I got a tradition for you.
施瑞德，5岁时我们就是好朋友
Schrader, you've been my best friend since we were 5 years old.
这是我知道的唯一的传统
That's the only tradition I know.
我搞砸了，真的搞砸了
I just messed up. I really messed up.
怎么了？
How? What happened?
我和施瑞德...
With Schrader.
巴特比在游泳池那边
MAN: I know Bartleby is by the pool.
天
Oh, my God.
什么？警察来了？
What is it? Cops?
糟了，我爸妈来了
Worse. Parents.
爸，妈，太好了！
BARTLEBY: Mom! Dad! Great!
嘿，各位
Hey, guys.
巴特比！小家伙！
Bartleby! Hiya, kid!
见到你太好了！
Hey, oh, it's so good to see you!
见到你太好了！ 你瘦了
Oh, it's great to see you. Ow. You look thin.
那边5个是你的死党？
There's five good ones right there for my college boy, huh?
嘿，爸
Hey, hey, Dad.
你...你在这做什么？
Wha-- What--What--What are you doing here?
家长日
Well, Parents' Day.
成为学院的一员感觉真好
What a wonderful idea on the part of the college, you know?
是，好吧
Yeah. Oh, right.
家长日，当然
Parents' Day. Of course.
大家好 欢迎来到家长会
Hello, everyone. Now, welcome to Parents' Day.
很高兴你们能来这里
And, uh, we're very glad you could be here.
我们有个不错的参观计划
Um, we have a wonderful guided tour planned
在校园四周转转
a-around the grounds and the campus,
向你们展示我们在这里做什么
Show you what we've been working on all year.
欢迎大家 打搅下
So, welcome one and all. VAN HORNE: Excuse me, everyone.
能让我说两句？
May I have your attention, please?
该死
Oh, shit.
我说怎么有臭肉味道
I knew I smelled bacon.
我是理查德·范霍恩
My name is Richard Van Horne.
范 霍恩 对
Oh, Van Horne, yes.
哈蒙学校的校长 我们最大的姐妹学校
The--The dean of Harmon College, our big sister school.
给他掌声 这是应该的
Give him a round of applause. He's earned it.
谢谢你的到来 很高兴在这看到他
Thank you for comin' by. Great to see him here.
他们是最大的姐妹学校
They are our big sister school,
谢谢他们的到来
and we are honored by their presence.
谢谢你不错的介绍，年轻人 但是玩笑结束了
Thank you for that nice introduction, young man, but the joke is over.
女士们，先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
南哈蒙理工学院
South Harmon lnstitute of Technology
不是我们的姐妹学校
is not the sister school of Harmon
或者什么也不是 在这件事情上
or of anything else, for that matter.
更像是堂兄妹，谢谢你的到来
More like cousins. Thank you for coming.
这可不行 任何...
It is not accredited. Any...
她也不是一个正式的教育机构
Nor is it truly an educational institution.
真的吗，巴特比？
Is this true, Bartleby?
都是假的，骗局
It is a sham, a fraud,
这会破坏其它大学的努力成果
that undermines the efforts of real colleges everywhere,
我请你和认证机构的人证实一下
and I invite you to confirm that
with the State Board of Accreditation.
上当的同学们
To all those students who have been duped,
明年申请的时候好运吧
good luck applying to schools next year.
基恩斯先生 我们的律师会联系你
And to Mr. Gaines I say you will be hearing from our attorneys.
家长日，和我预料的一样
Wow, Parents' Day. Man, I wish I would have thought of that.
我做到了
Oh, that's right, I did.
顺便说下
Oh, and by the way,
如果你遇到这里的产权所有者
if you, uh, if you see that lease holder of yours,
能跟他说 当他发现这些骗局
will you tell him that his lease automatically breaks
会自动中止协议？
when he's found guilty of fraud?
很好，谢谢，D
Cool. Thanks, D.
G?
Er, was it G?
对了，是F 再见F
That's right, it's F. See you, F.
听我解释
Guys, I can explain. Mmm-mmm.
你做了些蠢事，巴特比
You have done some stupid things in your life, Bartleby,
但这...
but this...
收拾好东西 回汽车上吧
You get your stuff together. You meet us in the car.
难以置信
This is unconscionable.
真可笑
STUDENT: Ridiculous.
嘿
Hey.
如此...
So,
都是假的？
none of this was real?
不是真的
That's not true.
等等，莫妮卡
Wait, Monica. Monica, wait.
莫妮卡
Monica.
对不起
Sorry, man.
还好 我们努力了
It's cool. We tried.
# 让鼓手继续，让鼓手继续敲
# Let the drummer kick Let the drummer kick that
# 所有的联系
# Relations
# 创造的
# Creation
# 幽闭
# Incarceration
# 决定
# Determination
# 平等
# Equation
# 羞辱
# Humiliation
# 再生
# Reincarnation
# 境遇
# Situation
# 得意
# Elation
# 证明
# Identification
# 报复
# Retaliation
# 教育
# Education
# 灵感
# Inspiration
# 没有取代
# No substitution
# 方案
# Solution
# 结论
# Conclusion
# 让鼓手继续，让鼓手继续敲
# Let the drummer kick Let the drummer kick that
# 关系
# Relations
# 证明
# Identification
# 报复
# Retaliation
# 教育
# Education
# 让鼓手继续，让鼓手继续敲
# Let the drummer kick Let the drummer kick that
# Let the drummer kick Let the drummer kick that #
一点想法都没有？
Have you completely lost your mind?
各位，他们把大学定义为很多人
Guys, the state defines a college as a body of people
怀有共同愿望的高等教育
with a shared common purpose of a higher education.
那就是说我们也是 对不对？
Well that's us, isn't it?
我的意思是，你们知道 “高等”这个词是个宽松的定义
I mean, you know, with the word "higher" kind of loosely defined.
对，他完全六神无主
Uh, yeah. He's completely lost his mind.
不不，听着 我们要做的
No, no. Listen, all we have to do
就是在认证机构之前
is go before the state accrediting board,
向官员递交我们的案子
with a licensed administrator, and just present our case.
B，让我们减少损失吧？
B, look, let's just cut our losses, okay?
我们在这谈什么？
What are we talking about here, huh?
再谈一张无用的纸
We're talking about a stupid piece of paper.
我的意思是 如果只需要一张纸
I mean, if a stupid piece of paper
就可以让我们被接受
is what's gonna make us acceptable,
我们就试一试 为什么不？
then let's go for it. Why not?
你们记住，这不只关系我们？
'Cause you gotta remember, it's not just about us anymore, okay?
关系到南哈蒙的每个人
It's about everyone who went to South Harmon.
(CLAPPlNG)
伟大的演讲
Ah, great speech.
我获得了灵感 我被它感染了
I was inspired, I felt inspired by it.
谢谢 我在做个巡回
Thanks a lot, I'm-- I'm taking it on tour.
你在做什么？
What are you doing here?
不知道 我得去拿些东西
Aw, I don't know. I had-- I had to pick up some stuff.
香紫苏油，茄子 橄榄油，玉米棒
Some sage. Eggplant. Olive oil. Some Funyuns.
等等
Wait a minute.
来吧
Come on!
你不是要去申请鉴定吗？ 是不是？
You're the one that applied for accreditation, aren't you?
有些人必须要站出来，明白？
Well, someone had to do it, you know?
我们不能低头活着
We all can't live with our heads up our asses.
- 不同意 - 我不太明白
I disagree. I--I don't get it, man.
你说过你不想参与
You said you didn't wanna be a part of this thing.
我本不想参与其中任何事情
I didn't want to have anything to do with it.
我原本想成为施瑞德家第四代 去哈蒙的人
I wanted to be the fourth generation of Schrader to go to Harmon.
但我后来意识到
But then I realized,
我更想成为家中
I would much rather be the first generation of Schrader
第一个去南哈蒙的人
to go to the South Harmon lnstitute of Technology.
说完了，行了吧？
I said it, okay? I said it.
所以你说
So you're saying,
你想成为南哈蒙的头？
you're saying you want to be a S.H.I.T. head?
我说我想成为南哈蒙的头
I'm sayin' I want to be a S.H.I.T. head.
我想成为南哈蒙的头
I wanna be a S.H.I.T. head.
太好了，欢迎你回来
Yeah, man, well, it's good to have you back, buddy.
太好了 耶！
Yes. Yeah!
呀！
Yay!
好了 我们开始吧
All right, so we're doing it.
谢谢这位领导 我们周五有个帮手了
Thanks to this S.H.I.T. head, we got a hearing set for Friday.
别害怕 我撑着
Don't sweat it, kid. I'm all over it.
好的，记住 本，这次很严肃，明白？
All right, please remember, Ben, this is serious, all right?
要是失败了 我要去监狱
If this doesn't work, I'm going to prison.
别担心，你还年轻 没什么
Oh, don't worry, you're young. Your butt can take it.
你好，先生 我们来自南哈蒙
Hello, sir. Um, we're from South Harmon.
我们3点在A号房有听证
We have a 3:00 in Hearing Room A.
好的，你们的会已经挪到主厅了
Okay, actually your meeting room's been changed to the Grand Hall.
为什么？ 那边更宽敞
Why the change? It's bigger.
- 他们怎么... - 罗莉叫来的
BARTLEBY: How did they... SCHRADER: Rory called them.
整个学校？
BARTLEBY: The whole school?
我得做点事情
I had to do something.
本次教育局的会议马上开始
This meeting of the State Board of Education will come to order.
今天要听证
Today we'll be hearing the case for accreditation
南哈蒙理工学院的案子
for the South Harmon lnstitute of Technology.
你们的案子是由代表
Your case for accreditation is being contested
哈蒙大学的范霍恩
by Dean Richard Van Horne,
递交
representing Harmon College.
(STUDENTS BOOlNG)
(GAVEL POUNDlNG)
失败者
STUDENT: Loser. Loser.
按照规定
In order to become accredited,
一所学校有3个标准
a school must meet three requirements.
必须有设施，课程和教员
You must have a facility, a curriculum and a faculty.
请陈述
Please state your case.
到你了，孩子
You're on, kid.
什么？我以为你会来处理 你干什么？
What? Wha-- I thought you were gonna handle this. What are you doing?
第一条例 作为一号人物
Rule number one, lead with your star witness.
没人比你更了解学校和这帮人
Nobody knows South Harmon and these kids better than you.
所以，该你上场了
So, it's showtime.
让我们干掉他们
Let's kick some ass.
你会很棒 做你该做的事
You're gonna be great, man. Just go do your thing.
拿出勇气
Sling some bull.
天
Oh, God.
好
Okay.
啊
(CLEARS THROAT) Uh,
陪审团的女士先生们 谢谢你们
Iadies and gentlemen of the panel, thank you for meeting with us.
我叫巴特比·基恩斯 我是南哈蒙理工学院的
Um, my name's Bartleby Gaines and I'm the co-founder of
创始人
South Harmon lnstitute of Technology.
(ALL CHEERlNG)
(GAVEL POUNDlNG)
对不起，我的朋友
Sorry. Friends of mine.
很抱歉 首先
Um, I'm-- I'm sorry, first of all,
刚才你说的那三样是什么？
w-what were those three things that you listed?
设施，课程，教员
A facility, a curriculum and a faculty.
设施 好
Facility, right.
好的 我们的确有设施
Okay, well, we definitely have a facility.
我们有大教室和宿舍
Uh, we have a common room, we have dorm rooms.
有个滑板斜坡
Uh, we have a skateboard ramp.
提基酒吧
We got a tiki bar. Umm...
他们租了个旧精神病医院
They have leased an old mental hospital.
他们没有传统的设施
They have none of the traditional support facilities
和资源
or resources.
基恩斯先生  你有正式的运动设施？
Mr. Gaines, do you have a formal athletic facility?
好 正式的..你是指...
Okay, uh, by formal you mean...
不不，没有
No. No, we don't.
图书馆？
A library?
没有
No.
医疗中心？ 没有？
A health services center? No.
没有
No.
课程呢？
Your curriculum?
- 课程？ - 对
Our curriculum? Yes.
课程表？ 全面的开课列表？
Do you have a course book? A comprehensive list of your available classes?
那当然 阳光，你能...
Oh, yeah, absolutely. Uh, Sunshine. Can you...
(ALL CHEERlNG)
这是什么？
What is this?
我们的课程 这是我们在南哈蒙所提供的课程
Our curriculum. These are the courses we offer at South Harmon.
开玩笑 “闲散101”？
This is a joke. "Slacking 101"?
告诉我，基恩斯先生
Uh, tell me, Mr. Gaines,
保险杠的贴纸上有什么课？
how does one major in bumper stickers?
先生
BARTLEBY: Sir, um...
对不起，基恩斯先生
I'm sorry, Mr. Gaines.
看不到有价值的
I fail to see any merit
任何有学术价值的东西在板子上
or scholastic value in anything listed on that board.
好的，各位 能帮我解释？
Okay, uh, guys, you want to help me out here?
在“散步和思考”中
In "Taking A Walk and Thinking About Stuff,"
我们思考人生要做什么
we get to think about what we want to do with our lives
在一个减压的环境之中
in a stress-free environment.
“让他对你说202”是门艺术课
"Let It Speak To You 202" is an art class in which we discover our talents
我们通过调查个人经历 发现自身才华
by examining our personal life experiences.
“滑板234”我们建斜坡 来叫我们工程...
In "Skateboarding 234" we built a ramp that teaches us about engineering...
- 物理 - 空气动力学
And physics. And aerodynamics.
“摇滚222”
In "Rock Our Faces Off 222"
我们听音乐 抒发对迷失一代的担心
we listen to the music and lyrical angst of a lost generation.
同时摇滚到死
And we rock our faces off.
(STUDENTS CHEERlNG WlLDLY)
的确
They do.
目前有教员吗？
Do you have faculty present?
有的
Yes, we do, sir.
教员，站起来
Faculty, stand.
什么意思？
What is the meaning of this?
看，在南哈蒙 学生就是老师
See, at South Harmon, sir, the students are the teachers.
太荒谬了
Aw, this is preposterous.
学生不是也不能是老师
Students are not and cannot be teachers.
范霍恩校长说的对
CHAlRMAN: Dean Van Horne is right.
你必须有原则上的教员 否则无法被承认
You must have a faculty as defined by the state, or you cannot be accredited.
基恩斯先生 那你有没有教员？
Mr. Gaines, have you employed a faculty or not?
呃...
Um...
教员出列
Present and accounted for.
上帝保佑
Oh, for God's sake.
亚历山大先生 这个家伙已经很长时间不敢了
Dr. Alexander, this man has not been a part of academia for three decades.
我们在哈蒙共事二十几年
We were on the faculty together at Harmon in our late 20s,
后来他被炒了
and he washed out.
他是酒鬼，老了 有些疯狂行为
He's a drunk, he's a degenerate, and he's looney tunes.
嘿，混蛋！你在说我舅舅！
Hey, asshole! You're talking about my mom's brother!
- 坐下！ - 好
Oh, sit down! Okay.
嘿！你为什么不把博士学位带来塞到你屁股下？
Hey! Why don't you take your PhD and shove it up your A-S-S?
(STUDENTS JEERlNG)
(GAVEL POUNDlNG)
安静！别乱套！
CHAlRMAN: Settle down right this minute!
刘易斯校长！坐下！
Dean Lewis! Sit down.
安静！
Order!
(GAVEL POUNDlNG)
我失控了
Couldn't help myself.
那么，基恩斯先生 这是真的？
CHAlRMAN: So, is that it, Mr. Gaines?
你们有个正式教师 来为300多名学生服务？
You have one formal teacher for upwards of 300 students?
基恩斯先生？
Mr. Gaines.
回答我的问题
Answer the question.
我不准备回答你的问题
Nah, I'm not gonna answer your question,
因为你们已经打定主意
'cause you guys have already made up your minds.
我是拒绝方面的专家
I'm an expert in rejection,
我能看清你们的面目
and I can see it on your faces.
太遗憾 你们的裁决和我们预料的一样
And it's too bad that you judge us by the way we look
你们没有理解我们
and not by who we are.
这是因为你们想我们和他们一样
Just because you want us to be more like them
但事实上我们不喜欢这样
when the truth is we're not like them.
我为我们所做的事情而自豪
And I am damn proud of that fact.
(STUDENTS CHEERlNG)
太棒了！
Rock on!
我的意思是
I mean,
哈蒙学院有它一百多年的历史传统
Harmon College and their-- and their 100 years of tradition.
但传统是什么？
But tradition of what?
欺压同学
Of hazing kids
羞辱看不惯的人
and humiliating anyone who's a little bit different?
给孩子们很大压力
Of putting so much pressure on kids
导致压力过大而失常 染上毒瘾
they turn into these-- these stress freaks and caffeine addicts.
你这个冒牌学校在诋毁真正的大学！
Your phony school demeans real colleges everywhere!
为什么？为什么不能共存？
Why? Why can't we both exist? Huh?
你们有你们的规则
You can have your grades, and your rules
你们的构成 你们的象牙塔
and your structure, and your ivory towers,
而我们做我们自己的
and then we'll do things our way.
为什么要遵守你们的规则？
Why do we have to conform to what you want?
你的课程是个玩笑 而你，先生，你是罪犯
Your curriculum is a joke, and you, sir, are a criminal.
知道什么？ 你是罪犯
You know what? You're a criminal.
因为你剥夺了这些孩子的创造性和激情
'Cause you rob these kids of their creativity and their passion.
这是真的犯罪
(ALL CHEERlNG) That's the real crime!
- 对 - 也许他是对的
Yeah. Maybe he's right.
你的父母呢？
Well, what about you parents?
系统是为你设计的？
Did--Did the system really work out for you?
它教你顺从你们的心
Did it teach you to follow your heart,
做个顺民？ 都很听话？
or to just play it safe, roll over?
你们呢？
What about you guys?
你们一直想做学校行政员？
Did you always want to be school administrators?
亚历山大博士 你有什么梦想？
Dr. Alexander, was that your dream?
也许没有 也许想做诗人
Or maybe no, maybe you wanted to be a poet.
或者魔术师，艺术家
Maybe you wanted to be a magician or an artist.
或者只想周游世界
Maybe you just wanted to travel the world.
看,我...撒谎了
Look, l--l--l--I lied to you.
我对所有人撒谎 非常抱歉
I lied to all of you, and I'm sorry.
爸，尤其是你
Dad, especially to you.
但绝望之余 有些事情很激动
But out of that desperation, something happened that was so amazing.
一生有很多可能
Life was full of possibilities.
难道这不是你们最后的要求？
A-A-And isn't that what you ultimately want for us?
作为父母，我的意思是 便是“可能”
As parents, I mean, is--is that, is possibilities.
今天我们来这请求你们的批准
Well, we came here today to ask for your approval,
有些事情发生了
and something just occurred to me.
我不在乎！
I don't give a shit!
谁在乎你们的批准？
Who cares about your approval?
我们不需要你的批准来告诉我们 什么才是真的
We don't need your approval to tell us that what we did was real.
因为真相总是掌握在少数人手里
'Cause there are so few truths in this world,
当你发现了 你就明白
that when you see one, you know it.
我明白这是一个真相
And I know that it is a truth
真正的学习发生在南哈蒙
that real learning took place at South Harmon.
无论你是否喜欢 它是事实
Whether you like it or not, it did.
不需要老师，教室
'Cause you don't need teachers or classrooms
以及虚浮的传统或者金钱来学习
or--or fancy highbrow traditions or money to really learn.
只需要大家有着提高自己的愿望
You just need people with a desire to better themselves,
这在南哈蒙已经拥有
and we got that by the shitload at South Harmon.
所以你们继续 标榜你们的规则
So you can go ahead, sign your forms,
拒绝我们，打击我们 做你们想做的
reject us and shoot us down, and do whatever you gotta do.
这一点都没有关系
It doesn't really matter at this point.
因为我们不会停止学习
Because we'll never stop learning,
也不会停止成长
and we'll never stop growing,
我们不会忘记在
and we'll never forget the ideals that were instilled in us
我们的土地上灌输的理想
at our place.
因为我们是南哈蒙的主人
'Cause we are S.H.I.T. heads now,
我们也一直都会是南哈蒙的主人
and we'll be S.H.I.T. heads forever
无论你说的，做的，盖的
and nothing you can say or do or stamp
可以让我们改变！ 去他妈的！
can take that away from us! So go!
(ALL CHEERlNG ECSTATlCALLY)
随你们！
Go ahead!
各位
CHAlRMAN: Everyone,
请安静！
please, quiet down.
请大家安静
Everyone, please quiet down.
请安静！
Quiet down. Please.
谢谢你
Thank you.
基恩斯先生
Mr. Gaines,
你的陈述
your presentation was unorthodox,
有些另类
to say the least,
你的方法
and your methodology is
也值得商榷
questionable at best.
但是
However,
真正的教育目的是 激发学生的
the true purpose of education is to stimulate the creativity
激情和创造力
and the passions of the student body.
在这点上你成功了
And in that regard you have certainly succeeded.
我们不会拒绝改革
This board does not reject innovation,
但必须有所关注
but it must be watched carefully.
因此
Therefore,
南哈蒙理工学院
the South Harmon lnstitute of Technology
准许试用一年
will be granted a one-year probationary period
继续它的试验计划
in which to continue its experimental programs.
别这么快按我们的方式下结论！
Don't be so quick to judge us by the way we look.
恭喜
Congratulations.
(ALL CHEERlNG ECSTATlCALLY)
基恩斯先生？
CHAlRMAN: Mr. Gaines?
长号
Trombone.
什么？
What?
我想玩爵士长号
I wanted to play jazz trombone.
从来都不会晚，先生
It's never too late, sir.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 嘿 - 嘿
Hey. Hey.
在这做什么？
What are you doing here?
我不知道 我的生命中有很多事情
I don't know. There were just a lot of things in my life
原以为是真的 但最后却是假的
that I thought were real that ended up being fake.
因此，倒过来说 就会成真了
So, why can't the opposite be true?
(LAUGHlNG)
(WHOOPlNG)
这不是你们要走的方向 这是你们的迷茫
This is not your orientation. This is your disorientation.
你们已经朝那里走了很多年
You have been orientated for years.
别跟着我去发现 “我该去哪里搜寻？”
Don't come up to me, go "Where am I gonna get that?"
我没兴趣 你们自己去找
I'm not interested! You figure it out.
巴特比，我只想你做大事
I only wanted big things for you, Bartleby.
我想这件事做的不错
I'd say this is pretty big.
- 谢谢父亲 - 哈！
Thanks, Dad. Ah!
谢谢
Thanks, Pop.
好了，宝贝  好好过这学期
Okay, honey, I want you to have a good semester.
我会的，我爱你 莉齐，加油
Okay, I will. I love you. Lizzie, up top.
(EXCLAlMS)
热情不够 但我接受了
Wasn't enthusiastic, but I'll take it.
谢谢你的微笑
And I appreciate the smile.
施瑞德！没时间闲聊了，哥们
Schrads! Hey, no time for chit-chat, my friend.
我教“怀疑论401” 来吧！
I'm teaching "Skepticism 401." Sha-mon!
在南哈蒙 我们喜欢每学期开始
RORY: At South Harmon, we like to begin each semester
理清思绪 做深呼吸
by clearing our minds and doing some deep breathing.
我用香草醋 多明格拉斯酱做了85磅里脊肉
I got 85 pork tenderloins with balsamic vinegar demiglaze. Ka-blam!
埃迪，我们要把这些铁板三明治 给罗莉的自然课送去
Eddie, we gotta pack these paninis for Rory's nature walk.
就去！
Pronto!
谁去找个老师来给这些鸡肉祈福
And someone get a rabbi down here to bless this chicken.
明天我们要去犹太教
Tomorrow we're gonna go kosher.
南哈蒙让我有机会
HANDS: South Harmon actually allowed me the opportunity
挖掘对艺术的激情
to rediscover my passion for the arts.
所以我希望你们也是 所以用心体会
So I urge you guys to do the same. Let it come from the heart.
然它走进来 回归本色
Let it come from inside. And--And let the art speak for itself.
你同意？ 看着长家伙
You agree? Watch--Watch the tip.
打搅下
Excuse me.
喔哦
(CAMERA CLlCKlNG) Whoa, whoa, whoa.
要是你想拍 就拍好的一面
If you're gonna take my picture, you gotta take it from my good side.
呵，这四周没有人
Um, so there wouldn't happen to be anybody around
可以带我去看新宿舍了 是不是？
that could show me to my new dorm room, would there?
命中注定的 我让你的宿舍挨着我
As fate would have it, I recall your room being right next to mine.
真的？不是紧挨着的？对不对？
Really? They're not adjoining though, right?
不不 那是无法接受的
Oh, no, no, no. That would be totally unacceptable.
帮个忙 好好享受这里
And do me a favor. Enjoy your time here.
这四年 是你一生最好的时光
You got four years, these are the best years of your life.
到那时，你就会
And then, you're (BEEP).
(STUDENTS LAUGHING)
(BlRDS TWlTTERlNG)
(GASPlNG)
我告诉过你
I told you.
(YOU THINK WE SUCK PLAYlNG)
(MASH-UP OF MOVIE LINES PLAYING)